What is going on?
Today we're going to war.
We're gonna fight space.
Fisticuffs.
It'll be a fight for the ages.
And I'm gonna win.
Also, sorry, I was a little bit delayed.
I was making coffee.
In fact, let's calm down a bit here.
Let's just, you know, you know, take it easy.
We are gonna go to war, but not yet.
That comes in a little bit.
Dude, I'm so excited.
I actually printed all the hotkeys for the game, so now I have it on my second monitor.
I installed another mod, because people were saying I missed an obvious one in terms of graphics.
I installed restock.
Apparently it revamped some textures and stuff, so I missed that one.
Now that one's installed as well.
It's gonna be good.
Very nice.
And guys, look at the title of the stream.
I am fully and completely aware that I am in that part of the Dunning-Kruger effect right now, where I think I know more than I do.
And I'm gonna embrace it.
I'm not gonna be afraid of it.
So what we're doing, we're starting over on hard.
Because fuck it, we're going all in!
I know how this game works now.
We're going hard.
That's right.
No take-backsies.
The mission is the mission, and if we fail it, so be it.
That's right.
You can, uh, you can, uh, you know, make fun of me later if this doesn't pan out well, okay?
But think about it, man.
It's gonna be way more exciting, I think.
I've been thinking about it, like, all this time, you know?
Like, I wish I had played on hard from the start.
I had a feeling hard would be more fun, but, well, what else?
Maybe I'm completely wrong, and it's gonna crash and burn, and I'm gonna hate my decision.
But I don't think so.
I think it's gonna be amazing.
We're gonna take it slow.
We're gonna read the- the in-game manual.
We're gonna- Fucking calculate- No, we're not gonna calculate shit, that's too much for a stream.
But we are going to think hard about things.
You know?
Before we make any drastic actions or decisions.
And now that I know how to get into orbit really easily...
Bro, this game is my bitch.
I'm sorry, but it is.
Everything else is just an extension of that.
It's not even that hard.
Come on.
Mmm.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, this coffee's actually really good.
I nailed this one.
Mmm.
Normally, my coffee skills are like...
I get a coffee good 60% of the time, you know?
So, 40% of the time, the coffee is shit.
Which is weird, because...
I put the same amount of bean in there every time.
Same amount of water.
It's the same procedure.
Yet, somehow...
It turns out different.
I don't understand.
Not because it was easy, but because it was hard.
Exactly, Michio.
Couldn't have said it better myself.
If there was a nightmare mode above hard, would you pick that instead?
Probably not, actually.
The thing I'm so excited about, in terms of hard, was the little setting called, uh...
No reverting, you know?
We talked about it last time at the end of the stream that, oh, we can, you know...
Just pretend that we're simulating.
We're in the simulator, and then when it's really going down, you know...
But, I don't know, man.
Let's just go hard.
Let's just do it.
I feel like it's going to be fun.
You know, we're going to fuck up.
We're going to make some mistakes.
But it's going to be fun.
And that's what I'm here for, in the end anyway, right?
Exactly.
You don't get any take-backsies in real life.
And KSP is real life.
What about toggling revert safes off on your current save file?
Oh, I guess I could do that, actually.
I guess that would be an idea.
But, I mean...
I kind of want to...
I mean...
We gotta go hard, right?
We gotta do it.
I mean...
I'm feeling the Donnie Kruger.
You know?
It's in me.
I'm on that...
You know...
Peak.
The initial peak of the graph.
And then very slowly, we're going to start to fall down.
And we're going to reach the bottom and realize the error of our ways.
And then we're going to keep climbing...
Over time.
And realize that...
Oh, man.
We can't even get to that peak anymore.
But at least we're going to plateau a little.
We're going to have some people dying.
That's okay.
We're going to have memorials and we will never forget them.
What am I kidding?
Nobody's going to die onto my watch.
In fact...
We're going to play on hard today and there will be no deaths.
No deaths.
That's my prediction.
I feel good about it.
I actually watched a documentary about...
What do you call it?
Fuck, what's the word?
Space travel.
I re-watched some of the episodes of one of my favorite shows ever.
Which is called When We Left Earth.
You know, it's the show that talks about the Gemini missions and everything up to...
The Apollo missions and all that stuff.
Man, I'm so hyped about this game.
Like, I'm freaking consuming media related to it now.
I mean, not to KSP specifically, but like...
Just NASA and stuff like that, you know?
Very excited.
Guys, we're going to get started.
And there's the music.
I am going to...
You can't even see my screen.
I will make a new file.
You know what the last file was?
The last file was the simulation.
Now it starts for real.
We're going to call it...
Bro, I don't know.
I don't know.
What should we call it?
You guys have any ideas?
Hold on, let me check.
Dunning-Kruger?
I actually like that.
What about just Kruger Space Agency?
KSA.
It's actually an acronym for another game that's being developed right now.
By the old developers of...
KSP.
Okay.
Hard.
We're going hard, bro.
Let me actually see what else is different.
Okay, so a bunch of sliders are moving.
Okay, wait, wait, wait.
Do we do hard or do we do moderate and not turn these two on?
What do you think?
I'm actually getting a little...
Maybe we shouldn't do, like, full hard.
Hard.
Okay, I see people say hard.
We go hard.
There we go.
Guys, I'm jumping in.
We're doing this.
I got my coffee.
I got the mood, the motivation.
The mood and the mo...
I said that already.
But I got it.
It's happening.
Oh, flag.
Let's do...
I want the same flag.
I like my flag.
The little patch.
Where is it?
Oh, they even have a NASA flag.
That's funny.
Retro.
Yeah.
Oh, but wait a minute.
It says KSP on it.
Guys, I'm gonna be boring as fuck.
It's just...
This is the fucking Kerbal Space Agency.
No, wait.
It's program.
I'm an idiot.
This is the Kerbal Space Program.
The real one.
Oh, yeah.
What's up, Gene Kranz?
Let's...
I'm ready for you.
So, listen.
We have to upgrade this launch pad.
Almost immediately.
But let's not get too far ahead of ourselves.
First things first.
Mission control.
We're gonna collect so much science.
Gather scientific data from Kerbin.
You got it, man.
We take that.
Launch first vessel.
You got it, man.
Take it.
And that's the max.
Boom.
In fact...
I'm gonna do all that in one go right now.
Welcome to the...
Yeah, yeah.
Shut up.
We're in her front, Kerman.
I'm on a mission.
I'm going to make a rocket.
Today we're landing on the moon.
And we're gonna do all the other things.
And then, you know, insert the rest of that quote.
Whoa, this looks different.
Look!
Hey!
Okay, so that's what restock does.
It's just actually...
Looks like it's embellishing a little bit, though.
Like, it's not just textures.
But okay.
Looks cool.
What else did I start with?
Basic fins.
The mystery goo containment unit.
Oh, we should actually do that immediately.
Get some science going.
Nice.
Uh, then we need this thing here.
Whoa, look at that.
Fancy.
Huh!
Alright.
Let's make it, uh, yellow.
Okay.
Uh...
Science one.
And this will be...
Basic science...
Stuff.
Easy.
Uh, save it.
And are we ready for this?
Do we have people in the capsule?
We do have Jebediah in there.
We also have Bill, Bob, and Valentina.
I love the names.
Mmm...
I think we're ready, right?
Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
There we go.
Let's go, man.
Let's go.
So, hold on, hold on, hold on, hold on.
Uh, we have to...
Gather scientific data from Kerbin.
Easy.
Launch first vessel.
I mean, okay.
Science incoming.
This is Kerbal Space Program.
The real one.
The other one was a simulation.
It wasn't real.
Hold on to your hats and goggles, people.
We may have some casualties.
Before I launch...
Um...
We have to do...
A crew report.
Oh!
I also installed something else, by the way.
I installed a visual thing for science.
Where they will...
It's like a community thing.
Where a bunch of people add...
Little descriptions to the science stuff.
Because I noticed last time, it was just the same thing every time.
So, I found that while, uh...
Installing the mods.
So, we now have that.
So, look at this.
You're not sure this is the right place to be.
I'm not sure if that's new or not, but...
That's not a lot of science, by the way.
I wonder if that also got affected by the hard difficulty.
I feel like I got more science from a crew report last time.
But who knows.
Let's do the mystery goo.
The goo doesn't seem to be doing much right now.
Okay.
Keep it.
Um, let's also...
Let me see.
Oh, look at our flag there.
So nice.
Kerbal Space Program.
The real one.
We're going to EVA.
We are not gonna jump off, because I can't get back in.
We learned that lesson the hard way last time.
EVA report.
It seems we are on our home planet.
Boom.
Wonderful.
Anything else I can do right now?
Hmm.
Okay.
Board.
Okay, so we have to, uh...
Hold on.
We gotta do...
Throttle.
We also have this now.
Toggle SAS.
Stability Assist.
RCS is, uh...
Something we cannot do yet.
Um...
I'm trying to see here.
We kinda need a checklist, don't we?
Before we launch.
I guess always check this.
Make sure that we don't parachute immediately and all that.
I think I'm ready, man.
Uh...
Oh!
We also...
We can't come straight down.
We can't become a missile.
So we're gonna have to turn out slightly for wind resistance.
Okay.
Here we go.
Whoa, that's sensitive.
We gotta turn more.
Turn more.
Oi, oi, oi, oi, oi, oi.
Hopefully this is fine.
Jebediah?
We're gonna get you home.
We cannot be coming down as a missile, by the way.
We have to sort of make sure that we have enough surface area to slow down.
Oh, I'm coming for you, moon.
I'm coming for you.
The real Kerbal Space Program...
...has begun.
Okay, so we're nearing the top of the parabola right now.
Maybe I should start angling myself, sort of.
I guess we want to angle it towards her butt.
At all times.
Well, we're gonna come down like this.
Okay, we're speeding up.
We're on our way down.
Wait, maybe I should just parachute now?
I'm not sure.
Actually, we're a little higher.
I don't know if I should parachute yet.
Keep it on this.
Maximum surface area.
Imagine I die immediately.
Uh-oh.
I'm just gonna...
I'm gonna parachute.
Fuck it.
Disable this.
Oh, shit.
I should have done that.
Uh-oh.
Wait, wait, wait.
Maybe it's fine.
It's fine, actually.
It's fine.
We're totally chilling.
Look at this easy mode, bro.
Oi.
Okay, dude.
The stability assist is nuts.
Feels like cheating.
Wait, is the parachute different?
Maybe that's also part of the restock.
I feel like it looks different.
Could just be me.
Guys, we have done it.
The first successful launch.
I told you it was easy.
Slow down.
The mission is not over yet, though.
We can easily drown.
Actually, I don't know if you can drown in this game.
I'm actually kind of scared to leave the capsule right now.
Actually, I could turn it.
That is the hatch, right?
Oh.
You hope they made the spacesuit waterproof as well as spaceproof.
Keep it.
What about crew report?
Oh, wait.
Overwrite?
Um.
I guess I want to overwrite because I can always get the report from the launch pad, right?
Yeah, let me actually do that.
We're going to crew report.
Overwrite.
You don't need to worry about pirates, right?
Surely they're only after regular ships, not spaceships.
I don't see any ships.
Okay, we did it.
Easy peasy.
Lemon squeezy.
Cheers.
That's a coffee sip.
We got some signs.
Immediately, we're going to...
Oh, did I actually...
Nice.
We did the contract.
Now we have a bunch of new ones.
Let's see here.
Obviously, this one...
...is an obvious one.
Test swivel liquid fuel engine splash down at Kerben.
I don't even have that one.
I need to...
I need to do science.
Okay.
So here, I definitely want this.
Whoa, they...
They look different now, for sure.
Yeah, it definitely added some kind of flavor to this.
Okay.
We can't buy this yet.
And how much science?
I have 11 science, so I can only get this.
But I guess I want this anyway.
Thermometer?
That looks very different, too.
The other one looked kind of flat.
Yeah.
We need this.
More science, right?
I'm actually thinking...
I think it's the right choice to go this way.
You know?
The more science instruments we get, the more science we can get.
And that way, we can unlock more.
This is almost like a bottleneck for the rest of the tree, is what it feels like to me.
Okay.
Now that that is done, um...
Also, what was this?
Okay, wait.
I don't want to worry about that right now.
It's too much.
Astronaut complex.
Should I be hiring new ones?
Does it cost money?
Let's just leave it as it is.
We're not going to touch it yet.
Um...
Mission control.
We definitely need a contract.
Isn't it just escaping the atmosphere?
That's like the obvious one, right?
Let's take that one.
Oh, yeah.
And...
Test a parachute and flight over Kerbin?
I mean, I'm going to have to do that at any point anyway, right?
Test MK-16 parachute.
Add Kerbin.
We need to be flying...
Between 2 and 5,000 meters.
And a...
Very specific speed.
This could actually be difficult.
But let's do it.
I mean, we have to use a parachute anyway.
Okay, next mission.
The next mission, baby.
Now we have a liquid fuel engine.
We also have this now.
Don't think I need these yet.
I don't know.
Definitely a thermometer.
Let's put that on, too.
I'm going to put it over here.
Yeah.
That's good.
And...
Cargo.
All right.
So that's the parachute we need to test.
So basically, right now, this mission is all up...
This is science, too.
This is, like, slightly more advanced.
Or slightly more...
Less basic science stuff.
You know what I mean?
It's not quite advanced yet.
It's not what I would say.
The idea now is we want to leave the atmosphere.
That's the goal of this mission.
And come back alive.
Get rid of this.
So for that reason, we are going to need to use a decoupler.
Nice.
Also, can I change the color on this?
Hey, that's kind of cool.
That's also cool.
I really like the white one here.
Looks nice.
Um...
What else?
Oh, then we need a fuel tank.
Let's get multiple.
I'm like an expert already.
Let's see.
Let's make these black.
That looks kind of nice.
It's all about the looks, you know?
It's important.
Okay.
Let's add a...
Fuel engine.
Whoa.
Hey, that looks kind of cool.
Nice.
I actually really like that.
Cover it up.
I wonder if this adds more mass, though.
Technically, it should, right?
Let's not do that.
Yeah, this is fine for now.
Then we need another decoupler.
To cover that.
And then underneath...
I guess we can use this.
For sure, we should be able to...
Oh!
I also need to be wary here.
So we're using 5,000.
But we have like 80,000.
Who cares?
The question is, do I even need this much fuel to leave the atmosphere?
I don't think I do.
This may be enough.
Okay.
So we have these two science experiments.
I'm planning to do those while flying this time.
So it's different, you know?
So this is the first stage.
We separate.
We burn.
And maybe I actually combine these.
And then at the very end, we separate that.
And we parachute down.
I like it.
I do like it.
Yes.
Okay.
Let's do it.
Is everything ready?
Just double checking.
Okay.
I think we're good.
I'm gonna launch.
Wish me luck.
Woohoo!
Oh my god.
Here we go, baby.
So escape the atmosphere.
Oh!
We also have to...
deploy the parachute under very specific circumstances here.
Or conditions, I mean.
So we gotta be...
That's a very narrow speed range, though.
Holy shit.
Between 2,000 and 5,000.
Okay, that's fine.
Flying, of course.
Uh...
Yeah.
Okay, here we go, here we go.
You ready?
Speed.
And...
Oh!
Jebediah!
We're gonna...
We're gonna slowly sort of angle it towards the water again.
We can get a nice splash down.
Maybe I observe this now.
The cool jiggles and wobbles.
Love it!
Love when it jiggles and wobbles.
Uh...
Lock the temperature.
Yep.
Ambient weather temperature is the definition of...
Beach weather.
Okay, cool.
Separate!
I'm gonna go slightly this way.
Also, I shouldn't go too fast, actually.
Hold on.
Need to see...
Uh...
When do I leave the...
It was like...
I don't know if it's enough.
Let's just go a little faster.
Slow down a bit.
Oh, that...
Oh, I don't even have any fuel left.
Oh, okay.
Well, then I can't really do anything else.
Hopefully it's enough.
We'll see.
So, escape the atmosphere.
Oh, there's actually an atmosphere counter here.
I just noticed this.
Look!
I didn't even see this shit.
Well, there you go.
So, I guess when that reaches here...
We're out.
Wait, am I even gonna escape?
Okay.
This may not be enough.
Uh-oh.
Dude, the rocket looks nice.
Look at this.
Oh my god, it's so pretty.
Very nice.
52.
Okay.
Ah, we may not make it, bro.
We're slowing down fast.
It's...
The needle is moving super slow.
Let's do a crew report while we're up here.
The mountains rise up from the grasslands of Kerbin.
They seem so much smaller from up here.
They do.
I mean, they also seem kind of small from down there.
I'm not gonna lie.
Lights on?
Oh!
Look!
There's a little light in there.
That's cool.
Okay, the needle is moving.
It still hasn't, uh, triggered.
We're starting to slow down.
Because we're reaching the...
The...
I guess technically apoapsis.
We're starting to speed up.
That means we're going down again.
Shit.
It's not triggering.
Oh, fuck!
No!
Look at the needle, bro!
Oh!
I should have had that last fuel tank on.
It's not enough.
Okay.
No...
No use crying over spilt milk.
Let's...
Separate.
And get ready for divorce.
Whoa, that's sensitive.
Whoa.
Whoa!
I need to keep this on, man.
Point it down.
Now it's all about surviving.
Jebediah is excited.
In fact, I want to see what he sees.
So, let's see.
What do you see?
It's a good view.
Okay, we're speeding up.
Should be fine, man.
We got this.
Maybe we can still do this one.
So, we have to be between 210 and 270 meters per second.
At this altitude.
That one's falling faster because it has less, uh, drag.
Given the shape of it.
Whereas, in our case, we have this big surface area.
Let me actually point towards my butt.
I can hear the air coming in.
We're slowing down.
Good.
Keep it aligned.
Oh my god, it's so sensitive.
Okay, so at 5,000, we need to be...
Okay, we're actually slowing down now.
Oh, we're gonna make it.
We are in the range now.
Look, it's even highlighted.
So now we just need to wait until we're below 5,000.
And then we pop the chute.
Come on.
Beautiful!
Main chute deployed.
Confirmed.
We may not have gotten to space.
But we did test the parachute.
Speed that up.
Oh yeah, look at that expansion there.
Wonderful.
Dude, I kind of want to try and do an EVA report right now.
I want to try and go on EVA.
Oh, I can't.
Cannot disembark while off of curb and surface.
Astronaut complex upgrade required.
Okay.
Well, shit.
Because we're not moving that fast.
5 meters per second, he can hold on, right?
Hopefully?
I don't know.
Maybe not, actually.
Imagine that's how he dies.
Oh god.
Okay, speed up.
Slow down a bit.
Splash down!
At Kerbin.
At 7 minutes and 25 seconds after launch.
Now I can do an EVA.
The problem is, we're not sort of on the side.
So is he going to drown?
Because, look at this.
I'm going to try and see if I can...
Oh, I'm butt-heavy, it seems.
It doesn't want to do it.
I'm going to try it, man.
For science.
Oof.
EVA report.
You have trouble swimming because your helmet is more buoyant than the rest of your spacesuit.
Okay.
That did no science?
That's crazy.
Okay.
We survived.
Second mission, guys?
Successful.
10.8 science earned, which means we can unlock more stuff.
How do they gain experience, though?
It says no experience gained.
Why not?
Why didn't he get any experience from that?
What do I want?
The Reliant engine is actually good.
I may have to get this.
And then...
Oh, but...
The science.
We may have to get this instead.
We get this, so we can get this.
And then we also have this, since we got it.
You know what I mean?
Oh, and heat shields!
Dude, we want heat shields.
Radiators?
Not quite sure about that one yet, but...
Landing struts?
Bro, I am dreaming of a landing right now.
Can't wait to land.
I'm going to research this.
We got him.
Oh, I like this song.
I'm not going to leave yet.
I like this.
It's the song of success, you know?
Of two missions going according to plan.
Well, one of them went a little off plan, but that was a miscalculation back at HQ.
We were so close, man.
Space is just without... out of reach.
Let's try again, shall we?
So, I think we just need...
Well, I guess I can just put a bigger, solid booster on this.
Or, I just add another little tank here.
Maybe that's better.
Is it cheaper, though?
400 bucks versus...
150!
Okay, well, in that case...
Oh, wait a minute.
What does the big one cost?
Uh...
Oh, I can't even...
I would have to add multiple of these.
And I guess I could.
I could just do this.
Maybe that's better.
Or even the smaller ones.
Nah, nah, nah, nah, nah.
Let's... let's... let's just add a little tank.
Small tank being added.
Boom.
Is that a different shade of gray?
It is.
Actually, I kind of like that.
That looks nice.
I don't know why it's showing gray and orange when there's no orange.
Am I colorblind?
What are you talking about, bro?
Okay, uh...
Science.
We have a press mat barometer.
Time to measure...
some pressures.
Let's put this guy...
up here.
We can't be covering up the sticker.
That's...
That's like, uh, heresy, you know?
Or whatever.
I wonder, though, like, do these actually have weight?
Or...
Yeah, they have mass.
Oh, wait a sec.
Dude, I'm a genius.
Check this out.
I want to be turning that way anyway, right?
Now it's gonna slightly lean that way.
That is so dumb.
It's like the silliest optimization of all time, but...
Okay.
It looks kind of funky, though, with this just sitting there, doesn't it?
I guess we have this.
Let's use that again.
And I guess we would...
Oh, we also have heat shield now.
We should use that.
All of this is gonna add weight, though.
Hmm.
It's okay.
We're gonna add this guy here.
And then, uh...
Heat shield.
Potality.
Thermal.
Yep.
This is pretty much the same layout I had last time.
Open this guy.
Oh, there's also different variations on this.
Wait, I don't see a difference.
Solid.
Trust caps.
No caps.
What?
No cap?
What's that mean?
Oh!
Oh, it's inside.
Okay, cool.
I just leave it like that.
That's fine.
Let's put this guy inside.
Oh, right.
This is kind of janky.
Uh, how did I solve this last time?
Um.
How the hell?
How does this work?
Oh, that's two of them.
Brother!
How do I make it...
Freaking...
Uh...
Rotate.
Oh, wait.
No, I need to place...
Wait.
Let me...
Let me do...
Wait a sec.
Maybe...
Maybe the heat shield is messing with everything.
A little janky for sure.
Oh, look at this!
Now it works!
Ha ha!
Uh...
Oh, we got a clip!
Not on my watch.
There we go.
That's beautiful.
Kind of looks like some kind of, um...
What do you call those tanks you go inside?
Where you don't feel anything.
You feel weightless.
It's all black inside, you know?
And you just lay there.
With your own thoughts.
Like a little...
I don't know.
Moose goes in there.
Okay.
Now we have the science stuff.
Uh...
Wait.
What an absolute local...
Local coordinate space are absolute.
Interesting.
I wonder how that's gonna be useful.
I'm gonna add this guy on this side.
Press mat.
Move it up slightly.
There we go.
And then we also have a thermometer.
Put it like there.
That's already beautifully placed.
Wonderful.
Close it up.
And then we need heat shield.
And then this.
Boom.
Oh my god.
It's beautiful!
Hell yeah.
Uh...
Let's check everything.
So what is the plan?
Oh, maybe I should...
Um...
Hold on.
I'm gonna save this.
Leave.
We need to get a contract.
We have one slot.
Uh...
Let's see.
Test heat shield in flight over Kerbin.
That sounds like something we could do.
To perform the test, use the run test option in the parts context menu when all test conditions are met.
Okay.
Wait, wait a minute.
Heat shield 0.625 meters.
Is that the one I have right now?
Heat...
Ah, shit!
It's not even...
It wants me to test the small one.
Wait, how do you even...
When do we...
Do you want to use this?
Like, I don't even have any parts that are smaller than this so far.
That's confusing.
Okay, well, we're not gonna take that contract.
Actually, I kinda like that it's randomly generated.
It's gonna be different every time.
Test a decoupler on a suborbital trajectory over Kerbin.
That sounds like something we could do.
160 kilometers, though?
That's kind of a lot.
I can't even get to space right now, though.
Maybe it's not good enough.
Then again, we have more...
I could add a bigger thruster to it.
Hmm.
Test hammer solid fuel booster at the launch site.
Okay, that could be a thing.
Okay.
Honestly, I think this one could be good.
Let's do this one.
TD12 decoupler.
We just need to add more power, you know?
To get up there.
Coupling.
Yeah.
So, I guess what we wanna do is to simply do the last stage of decoupling when we're at that height, right?
Because we're gonna fall down anyway, and it's totally cool.
So, check.
Regarding the fuel tank, maybe just keep adding on to it right now.
Because we wanna get up pretty high, right?
Okay.
I like this music.
It's kind of silly, but also kind of investigative and exciting, you know?
It is kind of silly.
I don't know if this one's gonna be able to, uh...
I can see that, actually.
Okay, so we do have a...
TWR more than one.
So, we are gonna get off the ground.
Um...
I mean, we can...
The thing is, though, we can't revert, right?
So, we have to think about this.
So, this is gonna get us...
Not too high up in the air, but then we have a lot more fuel.
Way more than last time.
And because we're higher up in the atmosphere, there's gonna be less air resistance, so we're gonna get more oomph.
More bang for the buck out of this engine up here, right?
So, I think that should be enough to get us up to...
At least to escape the atmosphere.
That one's a done deal.
The other contract, not so sure.
But we'll see.
We start with this.
This one gets separated.
Engine.
Boom.
Nice.
Wonderful.
This is exactly what we want.
Swivel.
What about...
Wait a minute.
Parachutes.
I think I want these, actually.
Slow down even more.
Because we're gonna be coming down at a crazy angle, right?
Let's add two of them.
Dude, that looks nice.
Sweet.
Put this here.
Why is it that there's...
It says there's three.
Oh.
Wait.
I don't understand what just happened, but okay.
Now there's two.
There's a, like, little asterisk on it.
Hmm.
Not sure why that is.
You know what?
Let's consult the manual.
Let's see what it says about parachutes.
If there's something about parachutes.
I guess it would be...
Rocketry.
Basics.
Parachutes.
What goes up does come back down.
It is much easier and more efficient to use parachutes when landing on bodies that have an atmosphere.
Compared to an engine burn, that is.
Just keep in mind that not all the places you visit have atmosphere.
That's true.
The parachute indicator.
The staging stack icon displays the state of each parachute.
The color of the background shows how safe it is to stage.
The icon's color shows the state of the staged chute.
Oh, yellow is risky.
Okay.
But you can do it.
Staged chutes activated semi-deployed?
Deployed and then cut slash shredded.
Got it.
Stability assist.
Let's read about this.
Kerbal pilots and many probes can use the stability assist system, SAS.
This can help to keep your vessel pointed in the desired direction.
The SAS modes can be seen to the left of the nav ball here.
Okay.
At its most basic, SAS will hold the heading of your vessel.
This is called stability mode.
More advanced modes allow you to target other directions, as shown with the matching nav ball markers.
Oh, okay.
Maneuver, prograde, retrograde.
Oh, this is the direction you want to go.
Normal, anti-normal.
I'm assuming...
Normal as in...
Normal to the direction of travel?
Radial's gotta be towards the planet and away.
Target, anti-target?
What's pushing that?
SAS uses control sources to apply force to get you back on target.
If there's not enough force, you may need to add more control parts, or a different design.
Note, these will consume resources.
You need to be mindful if you leave SAS engaged for a long time.
Oh!
So it's not for free.
It did feel a little crazy, didn't it?
I was like, this feels like cheating.
So there is a trade-off.
What resources, though?
Supplies.
Rocket fuels.
Surely the most common of resources, liquid fuel and oxidizer, are used together to power the majority of rocket engines.
Yeah.
Electric charge is used by all electronic parts and is critical for unmanned craft.
That makes sense.
Monopropellant.
Used mostly by the RCS.
This is the fuel for control thrusters.
Nice.
Xenon gas?
The fuel that is used by highly efficient ion engines.
Ion engines also need EC to run.
I see.
Cool, man!
Engines.
Okay, so we got these three variants.
Let's get some control.
These parts will allow you to input controls to the vessel.
Probe cores and manned pods.
Ah, reaction wheels.
Control surfaces.
Gimbaled engine.
And thrusters.
Neat.
Ah, yeah.
True.
Hey.
This is a nice looking rocket, man.
I kind of want to steal that design.
Hells yeah.
I want that.
Yeah, this is obviously a bad idea.
But it's cool that they actually calculate this stuff.
Symmetry.
Symmetrical sensibility.
When attaching components to vessels, the symmetry tools can help you keep things aligned.
With the center of mass.
Center of thrust.
Center of ligma.
Ligma balls.
Symmetry.
I'm sorry.
Angle snap off on.
Level of symmetry.
Note the misaligned thrust here.
Oh, yeah.
I mean, obviously.
This is like a common sense thing.
You don't even need to have this overlay on to know that this is a bad idea, right?
This is going to make the rocket turn that way.
Trying to add these manually is possible, but it will never be exactly balanced.
If you do it manually, you will likely require constant inputs to stay on course.
Or S.A.E.S.
Centered.
Center of thrust versus center of mass.
Right, you want the thrust to be below the mass.
Center of lift.
Oh, that makes sense.
Okay, we know this.
I don't want to exhaust the entire manual already.
We're going to take it slow and read it at, you know, times when it makes sense.
Okay, I think we're ready for this mission.
This is science 3.
This is now?
Uh, this is just advanced, actually.
Advanced science stuff.
Higher up, too.
Save it.
Oh, I wrote this wrong.
There you go.
Save it.
And...
Are we ready?
Let me see.
Dup, dup, dup.
Bup.
Bup, bup.
Nice.
Let's do this.
Dude, I freaking love this game.
Um, we are going to open this immediately.
Let me have a look inside.
What we got?
Uh, thermometer.
Did I lock temperature here?
I haven't even done that.
But maybe I shouldn't.
Because we're going to go high up, right?
We would rather do that up there.
Why can I not take multiple readings?
Should I not be able to do that?
Hmm.
What about this one?
No signs of adverse weather incoming.
We can launch at any time.
Let's just save these for later up, actually.
Sweet.
Okay.
Um...
SAS.
Speed.
We can also cut it with X.
Like that.
If we need to immediately stop.
Uh, you know.
Using speed.
Okay.
Will we leave the atmosphere?
I think the answer is a resounding, of course.
But getting to...
160,000 meters?
There's...
That's another question.
I don't think we can make it with this rocket.
But we'll see.
Let's see here.
We're off.
Jebediah.
Third mission.
It's beautiful.
Okay.
Get ready for stage two.
We got some clouds.
No problem.
Okay.
Stage separation.
Boom!
Let's start turning a little bit.
Slightly.
Oh, shit.
Oh, my God.
It's so unstable.
Okay.
Don't turn too much.
There's too much drag if we go sideways.
Uh-oh.
We're going way too fast, man.
Oh, that was it.
No more fuel.
Let's see what we can do here.
Okay.
I mean, that's definitely not 160.
1,000 meters.
But I think it's enough to leave the atmosphere.
Look at how close we already are.
I think we have done it, at least for one of these contracts.
Let's keep an eye on that.
I guess at this point, we don't need the rest of the rocket, so we can just disengage immediately here.
I love when you separate like that.
It's so freaking cool.
And look at this.
Easily achieved.
Will we reach 160...
No, we won't.
There's no way.
That has to be, like, double our height right now.
And...
Okay, well, it kind of looks like we may reach sort of double, but not quite double.
Are we gonna be super short again?
Right before the goal?
I love this view out the window.
The moon!
I yearn for the moon.
You shall be mine today.
So many stars.
There's the sun.
You know, this sort of rotation with the sun moving in and out of the frame reminds me of that one shot from Interstellar.
Well, many shots from Interstellar.
So pretty.
Let's speed up a bit.
We're slowing down.
Oh, we're actually almost reaching 160,000!
Oh, my God!
We're so close!
No!
We're right!
We're right there!
Not like this!
How are we short every time?
I feel like we need to rename Jebediah to Jebediah...
Short Kerman or something.
I just noticed, by the way.
His name is Kerman.
Like, last name.
Um, let's speed up a bit.
We're coming back down.
Jebediah, once again, you did not achieve the double whammy.
We shouldn't go too fast.
We have to be ready here.
Calm down.
Oh!
Atmosphere.
When does it start moving?
Now!
It's like 70,000 meters.
SAS.
Let's angle it towards...
Retrograde.
To maximize wind resistance.
So we can slow down.
Here it happens.
The air is becoming denser.
The heat shield.
Imagine sitting inside a capsule like this while this is happening.
Fucking hell, I would be so scared.
Okay, get ready for the first round of parachutes.
Droge chutes, deploy!
Go!
Woo!
Very nice.
I guess we can already deploy the next one.
Sweet.
Again, landing in the ocean.
I guess statistically...
I mean, if this was Earth, chances are we would land in the ocean, right?
I don't know how much of the planet carbon is covered in water.
Percentage-wise.
God, the game is so beautiful, man.
I can close this.
Oh, wait a minute.
While we're flying...
I forgot about the experiments we had.
Didn't even take any readings, bro!
Oh, my God.
Lock the pressure data.
100 million pascals.
That can't be right.
Oh, well.
Keep the data anyway.
What about mystery goo?
We're kind of bouncing a little bit here.
The goo jiggles and wobbles as the craft flies.
Nice.
What about this one?
Thermometer.
The air seems to be cooled by the water, and the temperature is lower than average here.
Crew report.
From this perspective, you can see the underwater topography.
Really?
Oh, I thought the main chute was already deployed.
I guess not.
God, this looks so cool.
Close it up.
Before we hit the water.
Another successful mission.
Jebediah...
Did you see him just now?
He was so excited.
He was flapping his arms.
That's what I do when I get excited.
Except I start clapping and, you know, making noises like...
One of those sea animals.
You know, that balance a ball on its nose?
I go like...
When I'm excited.
I rarely do it, because it requires a certain level of excitement.
That happens rarely.
40 meters.
Oh, by the way...
Wait a minute.
Let me check my cheat sheet here.
For keybinds.
Let's see here.
Toggle UI.
Oh, I'm going to be using this a lot.
Oh, yeah.
That is so nice.
Oh, I'm so happy I have the cheat sheet of hotkeys here now.
It makes it so much better.
Why is it...
Like, I click on this and it never registers.
I have to click again.
That has to be a bug.
Mm-hmm.
29 science in total.
Another successful mission.
This game is easy, bro.
If there was a nightmare mode, I would have picked it.
Just saying.
Okay, what's next?
General rocketry.
I think I like that.
I like generals and I like rockets.
Stability.
Radial decoubler.
The TT-38K radial decoubler, like most other decoubblers, is equipped with a hopefully small explosive charge.
That will sever the structural linkage between itself and whatever it's connected to.
So with this, we are able to put things on the sides and have them shoot off to the sides.
Just like the space shuttle.
You know, with its solid rocket boosters on the side.
But I'm gonna take this.
Because I'm a G.
And we gotta be reliant.
Reliable operations.
Is what the doctor ordered.
Let's see what we can do here.
Oh yeah, we didn't reach 160,000.
Next time, we will.
Now though, we need another goal.
Test the RT-5 flea solid booster in flight over a kerbin.
Do I even have that one?
A flea solid fuel booster?
I guess it wouldn't show me this unless I had it.
To perform the test, activate the part.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So we have to be...
Oh, that's actually kinda awkward.
Wait, failure.
How do we fail it?
I guess if the offer expires?
Or...
Or what?
Wait a minute.
If you decline, you get minus three gold stars?
But I can just choose not to accept it?
Huh?
I'll just let it be.
Let it expire.
I don't care.
Test the swivel fuel engine splash down at kerbin.
Okay, so these ones we have to go somewhere.
Maybe this is not too bad, actually.
Last time I did it pretty easily.
It's just...
It's not a lot of money for it, you know?
Like, if you think about the vessel I'm making...
The vessel is costing almost as much.
How about wait?
We get an advance.
Ooh.
I just noticed.
Interesting.
So that's gonna cover the cost of the rocket.
So it's actually full profit, then.
That's not too bad.
What was this one?
Maybe I'll just take the orbit kerbin.
Wait, wait, wait.
One thing we need to do.
No, we need to right-click.
Oh, it's 100,000?
Was it that last time?
I think it changed, because we have a hard difficulty now.
We may have to upgrade this.
But that means we have 53,000 left.
But we gotta do it.
There.
It's been upgraded.
Science 1, 2, 3.
I like it.
Mission flag.
Oh, so this is like a fast way to select stuff you've already made.
Without having to go in here.
Okay, that's kind of cool.
But let's grab a mission.
Let's just take orbit.
We're gonna go straight to orbit, man.
I'm feeling it.
Now that we have new boosters.
And we also have a new engine here.
Like, look at this one.
Oh my god.
We need that.
And Reliant.
This one is a problem.
Because it doesn't have any gimbal.
So the steering is gonna be a little problematic on that.
This is something we have to keep in mind.
What else did I get?
A bigger fuel tank.
Let me think.
What am I doing right now?
I guess we just wanna go to orbit.
That's like the goal.
Because if we go to orbit, we're also automatically gonna do this one.
Easy, right?
So the goal is orbit.
Orbit, it is.
And we're gonna bring science with us.
Let's get rid of these.
Delete that.
Let's take...
Let me think.
How many do I want?
I'm trying to think of the rocket I made last time that went to orbit.
I forgot how I did it.
It may have been something like this.
And then...
Obviously we need a bigger booster down here.
So we're gonna take the new big one.
Back.
Thumper.
Filled with a new, even more volatile fuel.
The back offers semi-reliable performance at a good price.
Oh yeah, it actually has more thrust.
At sea level and in vacuum.
Oh, that's the flea!
Ooh, okay, so I did have it.
Maybe we can do that quest.
I'm putting this one on.
I think this...
is good enough to go to orbit, man.
I think we got it.
It's as simple as that.
How much does it weigh?
15 tons.
Okay, so remember last time?
I couldn't get it up under 18 tons.
You know what I mean?
So I had to upgrade the pad so that I could get it up.
So maybe I need to add more, actually.
Because we are only at 15.
Hmm.
Maybe we add another stage.
Three-stage rocket, maybe.
I actually kind of like that.
Yeah, I like it.
Oh!
We're also...
Check this out.
We're gonna...
This shall become a Reliant engine.
Like that.
Because then we get more oomph, you know, at the start.
And then when we are up here, we do another stage separation.
Maybe I add one more tank.
Just one more.
Like this.
This way we can control a little bit more.
Oh, but wait a second.
Wait a second.
The problem here...
Is that this is not gonna give us any steering.
The Reliant is not gonna give us any steering.
And at this point, we're gonna be pretty high up.
Remember last time, I couldn't turn in time.
So I think we actually do need...
To change this to be a swivel.
I hate to say it.
It needs to happen.
And then we get rid of this.
And I think...
Maybe this is fine.
Keep it simple, you know.
That is a lot of...
Maybe I cannot lift all that, actually.
Get rid of one.
I also need to look down here.
So we have 884 Delta V.
Is that calculated at sea level, though?
How do I know?
Sea level?
Wait, what is changing?
Oh, okay.
So it is showing...
Ah, okay.
So it is sea level.
Okay.
And this one has...
Let's say this one takes us to...
I don't know.
20 kilometers?
Altitude 20.
Wait, I can't write 20?
Okay, 20.
Which means this one will then have...
More Delta V, right?
Because you're gonna be in less dense air.
And of course, further away from the planet.
God, I don't know.
Okay, fuck.
Sea level.
Fuck it.
Let's just try it, man.
How much does...
It's costing 8,000.
It's not even that much.
It's pocket change.
We're chilling.
It's no problem.
This is good.
This is a good rocket.
This will take us to orbit.
Let's just double check everything.
So this one, and then...
Oh, we need a separation down here.
That one.
Separate.
Boost.
Nice.
And then...
Separate.
Shoot, shoot.
Nice.
Very good.
This is it.
Maybe we add a little thingy down here.
Payload...
No.
God, where is it?
I'm looking for...
Fence.
Am I...
What?
There.
Basic fence.
We're gonna add...
Four.
Dude, looks nice, doesn't it?
Dude, look at that.
Beautiful.
Hell yeah.
This is now...
Orbiter...
One.
We go high...
And...
Stay high.
Yes.
Save it.
Very nice.
I'll be ready...
To rock this city.
Diddle it, did, did, did.
Did, did, did, did, did.
Oh my god, it's so beautiful.
It's so beautiful.
I wanna cry.
Okay.
Speed.
Uh, SAS.
Jebediah, are you ready?
Yes.
Good.
Let's go.
And we're off.
Look how stable we are, man.
I'm trying to turn slightly to the right already.
Even though there's not much, uh...
Control authority right now.
But there will be in a second when we get the swivel up and running.
Let me see my contracts.
Boom!
That's gonna fall straight down on the pad and destroy everything.
Okay, now we can turn.
I'm gonna start turning slightly.
Not too much.
Dude, I can feel it wanting to spin out of control if I go too far.
Maybe go a little further.
We have to start getting more, uh, horizontal here.
Alright, the atmosphere is very thin now.
Uh, cut!
Let's have a look.
Dude, that is a beautiful parabola!
We're gonna get up there.
We're gonna start burning the shit out of this.
Okay, so we gotta go horizontal.
Look at that.
Jebediah.
We have left the atmosphere once again.
But will we get to 160,000 meters?
And more importantly, will we orbit?
Let's see where we are.
I'm gonna wait until we're a little higher up.
Less air drag, all that.
That's so pretty.
Where's the space center?
Is that the one right there?
Look at it.
Oh yeah, I can kind of see it.
We're so far away.
I'm gonna wait a bit more.
Let's also rotate this lightly.
And then we do SAS.
Boom.
Okay, are we ready?
Much fuel?
Oh, I don't even have that much fuel!
We cannot go to orbit.
There's no way we do it.
Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
So maybe...
I have an idea, I have an idea.
Instead of going to orbit, we're gonna do a...
an emergency switch up.
We are gonna try and get to 160,000 meters instead.
We're gonna disband the idea of orbit.
You have your orders, Jebediah.
Yes.
Now, we're gonna have to point along our vector, prograde, give it all you got.
Fuck, it's not even doing much.
Turn it even higher up!
Emergency burning!
Burn away from the planet!
Straight up!
Surely that's enough.
We're at 150 now.
Oh, no problem.
We are gonna make it.
And then we have to test the decoupler.
Ha!
We made it!
So now?
Now we have to do, uh, this?
Yeah!
And then we do science!
We have to have the planet in view, though.
So pretty.
Mystery goo containment unit.
Let's see what's happening to the goo.
Seems to have clumped into a sphere.
It also appears to have become brittle.
Nice.
Sick science!
That's a lot.
Then we also had...
This one?
The instrument reads zero!
Surprising.
What about the temperature?
The fact that you're over the highlands...
Does not change the thermometer's opinion...
On the coldness of space one bit.
The highlands?
Crew report.
It seems we are very much in space right now.
The sky seems to be mostly below us.
Hell yeah.
Look at that.
Look at our stage down there!
That's so cool, dude!
Oh, man.
It's so damn pretty.
Eve.
Duna.
Moho.
That's not a planet.
So something there.
No?
Okay.
Let's close this.
Get ready for the next stage of the mission.
Survival.
We're gonna be coming in at a steep angle.
Wait, is this some sort of connection that's being made there?
Look at this!
Kerbal Space and Island Airfield.
It's like we can see it.
Or maybe it's like a line of sight thing.
Yeah, we're not gonna orbit this time, but that's okay.
I feel like we always achieve the last goal in the next mission, you know?
We never achieve the actual goal.
It's always the last goal.
We're always a little short.
Once again, Jebediah living up to his new name.
Speed up a bit.
Look at our stage down there.
Orbiter 1 debris.
Floating away from us.
So nice.
We can go a little faster.
I do want to take in the views, you know?
In fact, can I see anything from in here?
Let me turn off this.
Oh, that's it!
This is the new way to view things.
We're gonna have to turn the vessel, though.
This is some of the most fun ever, just doing this.
Show me the planet.
Ah, we're...
Actually, we're aligned in such a way where we can't see the planet.
The planet is below our feet.
The moon!
Okay, get ready.
We gotta put our game phase...
Oh, we're gonna land in the darkness.
That's okay, though.
Point it along a retrograde.
I feel like the angle is not good here.
Like, I would put it more like this.
This looks more right to me, you know?
But maybe you should just trust the instruments.
Oh my god, look at that!
Whoops, wrong button.
Look at the planet, man!
That is so pretty.
Hoi!
Here we go.
We're approaching dense air.
Okay, I'm gonna...
I'm gonna trust the instruments.
I'm gonna point towards prograde.
Look at the angle!
It looks wrong, doesn't it?
Call me crazy.
This feels more right.
Oh, now it's switched as well.
Yeah, that's more like it.
Oh, we are lighting it up.
Look at this.
Oh, shit!
Yo.
That's fucking sick.
I can't see nothing.
I'm so afraid of hitting a mountain.
Parachute!
And?
I'm gonna do the next parachute now.
I think we're safe.
Like, nothing can go wrong now.
Dude, look at this!
How nice is that?
Main chute deployed.
Jebediah hasn't died yet, by the way.
Jewel.
I wonder if that's, like, a planet really far away.
Or if it's one of the closer ones.
Minmus.
That's definitely a planet back there, isn't it?
Why can't I?
Oh, Dres.
Yeah.
I'm getting comfortable with the controls here.
Splash down!
We have splash down.
And what a trip that was, huh?
We got science done, and we got one contract.
Complete it.
Look!
It didn't register again.
Like, I clicked.
Maybe it needs to, like, focus on the panel, and then when I click again is when it's actually registering.
We got more science out of that.
And you guys were questioning me putting hard mode, huh?
Come on, brother.
What are you talking about?
Okay, what's this?
Science Junior.
I feel like I need to do this.
Experiment storage unit?
After discovering that old snack boxes were also really effective at storing mystery goo and data tapes, Kerbal scientists created the experimental storage unit to help Kerbalnauts bring their valuable science back to Kerbin.
while avoiding the hazards of re-entry.
Rough landings and Jeb's piloting skills.
They're referencing Jeb directly.
That's kind of funny.
So wait, what is the point of this?
Like, you put the science in there and you throw it?
Wait.
Is it like...
I'm actually confused what this is.
What's the point of this?
I don't understand the description.
Am I not bringing the science home even without this?
That's what I'm doing right now.
The SC-9001 is a cutting-edge, self-contained laboratory.
Have you ever wondered what happens to something in zero-G?
Or have you ever pondered the truly meaningful questions?
Such as, what would happen if I exposed this to the rigors of stellar radiation, an unforgiving vacuum?
Comes with a complimentary notepad.
Recommended for ages four to eight.
Small parts inside make it not suitable for small children.
I wonder how long kerbals live.
Because obviously four to eight is a child in human years.
But maybe for kerbals, it's like...
It's adults, right?
They're adults at that time.
Not sure.
The Stay Putnik offers the ultimate solution in crew safety.
A lightweight sphere equipped with remote receivers and relay control input from the ground to the craft, it carries no crew at all, thus keeping them perfectly safe from all harm.
This device does require electricity to operate, however, and will cease to function if the power runs out.
The built-in battery should keep it going for about ten minutes.
Okay, but I guess you can add more batteries then.
That's cool.
That's like a way to test missions without putting anyone in danger.
I really like that!
Maybe I'll have to do that now.
Or I save up for this.
More engines and more fuel tanks could always be good, right?
Ah, but let's follow the plan I had, which was...
Oh, I can't even get this anyway, never mind.
I don't have enough?
Oh, shit!
I thought I had enough.
Okay, I guess I don't.
Well, that puts a stop to that plan.
Let's see the contracts.
Test heat shield.
Test a radial decoupler on an escape trajectory.
Oh, that's difficult, though.
That requires a lot of delta V, and we can't do that right now.
So, you know what?
Let's just go to orbit.
This is like the new primary goal.
It's just go to orbit.
It's still orbiter one, because we haven't made it yet.
So, it's still the same rocket.
We're just going to adjust it a little bit now.
Okay, so what is the issue?
I think the issue is...
Let me think.
I think we need more thrust.
I'm going to do something crazy.
Check this out.
We're going to take...
two of these...
and simply do that.
Holy fucking shit, bro.
4,200 delta V.
Thrust weight ratio of two.
That's perfect.
Let me move these down a bit.
So that they're aligned.
It needs to look nice, right?
I don't like this, though.
Like, isn't that kind of bad aerodynamically?
Maybe we can add something to that.
Wait, we can...
We can bring more people!
Oh, wait a minute.
We're going to...
We're going to discard them.
If we do this.
Like, this whole thing is going to fall in the ocean.
Alright, that's not a bad...
Hold on, that's a bad idea.
Never mind.
Bad idea.
Can't we put in something like this, though?
We can save the...
Save the boosters, maybe.
Uh...
I don't know how this is going to work.
Like, is this going to mess me up?
Aerodynamically, this doesn't look sound to me.
Uh...
But who knows?
Maybe I'm wrong.
I think it's fine.
So, wait.
Ideally, we want to...
Turn all three on at the same time, right?
And why is it like...
Can I not sort of...
I don't understand this system.
Like...
Can I not, like, combine them into one that says three?
Maybe not.
Otherwise, the rest of the thing is the same.
This is the only change.
We're going to go ahead and try this.
This rocket costs 10,000 credits to launch.
That's quite an expensive one.
So, we better bring home the bacon on this one.
We gotta orbit.
And when we get to orbit, we're gonna try experimenting.
Let's do it.
This has to be Orbiter 2.
No, no.
It's Orbiter 1.
Because we haven't gone to orbit yet.
Save it.
Go.
Oh, man.
It's starting to look like a proper rocket.
These two go off and then we separate.
Turn that on.
This one.
That one.
Beautiful.
Okay.
Whoa.
Oh, yeah.
We're gonna get quite high with this.
I'm a little scared.
Okay.
We are almost out of fuel.
So, it's gonna take us to, what?
12,000 meters or so?
It wants to point left for some reason.
Separate.
We're gonna start turning a little aggressively here.
Not too much, though.
There's still drag.
I guess SAS will keep it from going too crazy.
I feel like we needed to have started turning earlier.
Because we're already...
Holy shit, we're already at 40 kilometers.
Whoa.
Hold on.
Let me actually stop.
Take a look.
Yeah, that is quite high up.
And look at all this fuel we have left.
I think we can definitely get to orbit with this.
I just need to wait.
Let's prepare.
Turn it.
Yep, today is your lucky day.
You will finally attain your dreams.
Of reaching orbit.
And now align it along...
Here.
So we're exactly horizontal.
I think I'll start burning...
Let me see here.
Let's speed up a little bit.
Maybe like now?
No, a little further.
Because we are speeding up.
We're going quite slow.
Let's do it now.
And go.
I think we have more than enough fuel.
Oh, maybe not.
Maybe not.
It's not looking good, actually.
Uh-oh.
No.
Shit.
Oh, man.
Jeb.
Once again.
So close yet so far, man.
Damn you.
Let's do some science, at least.
Let's observe this ghoul.
It's clumped into a sphere.
Okay.
It reached minus three.
Huh.
That's funny.
Oh, well.
They can figure it out back at KSC.
Uh...
There's nothing there.
There's no science there.
Temperature.
The fact that you're over the highlands does not change.
Okay.
This is also the same experiment.
I guess we did the same thing last time.
Close it.
Perhaps we can do some of these experiments when we're splashed down or something.
For now, though, we have to separate.
This mission was unsuccessful.
10,000 bucks in the toilet.
Separate immediately.
We can start pointing opposite here.
Like that.
Actually, I kind of want to point more like this.
To prepare for...
The eventual downward slope here.
Let's just speed up a bit.
Oh, it's getting so dark.
Look at my stage back there.
So pretty.
Yeah, we're going to drop down right on the dark side of the planet right now.
Oh, it's dark.
Oh, shit.
The stars are coming out.
Let's slow down a little bit here.
Actually, we're going to come in at a pretty shallow angle.
This is going to look sick.
Jebediah is excited as always.
Just like me.
I'm not quite as excited as he is right now, but I'm pretty excited.
So we're going, like, extremely fast right now.
I'm curious to see...
...when we're going to start to feel the effects of re-entry here.
Because the faster you go...
...the less dense air you need to start feeling friction, right?
So we're at 80,000 meters now.
We're actually still speeding up slightly.
Which makes sense, I guess.
77.
Jebediah, you will come home.
Did we start looking at experiments?
No, that's too risky right now, man.
We're about to fucking...
...enter plasma.
Blackout stage.
No communications.
Still nothing, huh?
Actually, look at this.
I feel like this angle is better.
Ish.
Still no effects.
Oh, it's starting to heat.
Actually, maybe it was correct.
This...
Yeah, you can sort of see the alignment.
Yeah, you want to be like this.
Oh, man.
Oy!
Damn, that looks so fucking crazy.
Whoa.
Look at his shallow angle.
Okay, Jebediah is actually not even excited.
He's, like, focused right now.
He knows this is a serious moment.
This is the time for caution.
Imagine if we flip around.
I think we're cooked if that happens.
Like, literally.
Jebediah will become a...
...Christmas turkey.
No.
Thanksgiving turkey.
What the...
I think my other stage just...
...burned the hell up.
Something exploded in there.
Maybe some leftover fuel.
Oh, wait.
That sounds like thunder.
Drogueshoots.
Deploy.
Mission unsuccessful, man.
Damn shame.
Where are we touching down?
Speed it up.
Oh, wait.
Wait.
That's fucking grass.
We're not over water.
Where are we?
What is that?
Look at these little white things on the ground.
It's raining now.
Look at that over there.
What is that?
Wish there was a dark mode for the...
...UI.
I feel like I'm being flashbanged...
...when I turn on the UI.
We made it.
Oh, look at that moon.
Let's do some science.
See if I can click on this.
What's the temperature out here?
The temperature is quite pleasant...
...and would be a nice place to live.
I agree.
The goo we already observed.
I don't know if I should overwrite.
I think I'm gonna overwrite.
Reset goo canister.
Observe mystery goo.
The goo turns green with envy.
From Kerbin's grasslands.
Uh-huh.
Pressure data.
As you painstakingly jot down the data...
...you wonder why you couldn't just take it...
...from the morning news weather report.
Yeah.
I guess we're gonna have problems...
...getting funding soon.
The experiments we're performing here...
...are not exactly groundbreaking.
But hey, at least we haven't lost anyone yet.
Let's try and exit the capsule here.
Wait.
Crew report?
The crew is embroiled in an argument...
...over whether the grass is in fact greener...
...on the other side.
So are you telling me Jebediah is...
...talking to himself in there?
This guy has lost his marbles.
Look at him.
That's the face of a psychopath.
Calm as a Hindu cow.
I wish I had brought pants.
I'm telling you.
This guy is nuts.
Should I try and...
...let go?
I'm gonna let go.
Oh my god.
Dude, this grass is massive.
Or am I just...
...small?
EVA report.
Oh, overwrite existing EVA report?
Oh, the one I just did, I guess.
I'm an idiot.
Makes sense.
Deploy shoot.
Let me, uh...
...lower the visor.
No, remove helmet.
Ah.
Jebediah.
The question is, can we actually...
If I recover a vessel, am I also recovering...
...Jebediah?
Hopefully he's not...
...still in the grasslands.
We got 1.5 science.
That's it?
I can't be right.
17 funds recovered from parts.
One crew member recovered.
Wait a minute.
We didn't get the freaking thing?
Wait, wait, wait.
Uh, tracking station.
Uh, yeah.
Orbiter 1?
Recover.
Hey, okay.
There we go.
We got it.
Why isn't it just recovering now?
That's weird.
I guess they prioritize, uh...
...life.
And not the inanimate object.
Okay, there we go.
Sweet.
I thought we had a minor disaster on our hands.
But it's actually okay.
Oh my god, we're so close to 45 science.
We need a little bit more science.
So I have an idea.
Uh.
We're gonna take a contract.
We're gonna do a little bit of work here.
It's not much, but it's honest work, right?
Uh, let's see here.
Test hammer solid fuel booster at the launch site.
That sounds extremely easy.
We're gonna get one science for it, which is exactly what we need.
This is the mission that will turn everything around.
Activate the part through the staging sequence when all test conditions are met.
And this is just kerbin, launch site...
Oh my god.
Yes.
Absolutely.
Hammer.
This one.
Um.
Let me see here.
Save this one.
New.
And then we need...
Uh.
Parachute, of course.
Can't forget that we also have a guy in there.
Uh.
Hammer.
Dude, we're gonna be fucking...
Flying like crazy here.
Bad up.
Do we bring a little science thingy?
Let's actually bring a little bit of this, too.
They don't cost much, anyway.
Barometer.
Put this guy over here instead.
And this guy there.
It's always good to bring, right?
Get some more science.
Put this one down here.
And this should be pretty easy.
Let's see.
Um.
I could also just limit fuel.
But that's gonna make it go faster.
I don't want that.
We can do...
60 thrust.
Wait a minute.
Can I not just...
Wait a sec.
Let's say I do like this.
We have a thrust to weight ratio of 0.1.
We're not gonna take off.
But is it gonna count for...
Testing it?
I'm testing this.
We should...
We should just stand still.
Like, we should not be getting any lift at all.
In any case, let's just...
Oh, I guess I could've...
Dude, I'm an idiot.
I could've just put this one down here like this.
You know?
I guess I can still do that.
Maximum thrust.
I mean...
Wait, I can't turn it off.
Oh, that's gonna take a while.
Look at that.
Uh...
Do I exit while a solid rocket booster is going off?
That's...
Also, did I do the thing?
Oh, we did it.
Okay, nice.
That works.
Let me do some science then while we're at it.
Maybe we get a little bit of science.
I'll take it.
And...
Pressure.
Hey, look at this!
No signs of adverse weather incoming.
We can launch at any time.
Well, we already did launch.
And some temperature scans.
The temperature reading spikes suddenly.
Did somebody start the engines?
Well, we did, but we're not going anywhere.
Can I actually speed up while this is...
Oh, I guess you can't have the engine turned on while you...
But that's weird.
So what does that mean?
Does that mean your engine just stops in mid-flight?
That's hella weird.
Oh, I can just recover a vessel.
Ah!
Well, there you go.
I guess it's technically landed.
Haha!
We got some science.
We have enough for the next stage now.
Check this out.
Now I really have to think.
I think I need this.
We need this so we can get even more science.
Yeah.
I'm gonna do this.
Okay?
Um.
What time is it?
Year one, day one...
Is it morning or evening?
I think it's morning.
Could be wrong.
Let's see the contracts.
Uh.
Well, we want to get to orbit.
Let's actually do that now.
That was the main priority mission, right?
And I think we can do it.
Let's just do that now.
Hey!
Look!
The flag is back there too!
I just noticed that.
Sweet.
I will open up my thingy here.
And we're gonna do...
Side...
No.
Orbiter...
One.
That one.
We're gonna iterate on this design.
So last time...
We just didn't have enough.
Right?
Oh, wait a sec.
I remember what I did last time now.
How I got to orbit.
I wasn't even using solid rocket fuel.
I was going full liquid, remember?
That was the tech.
So we start by using reliance.
And then we switch over to swivel.
Like that.
Nope.
There you go.
Look at that.
That's beautiful.
We can even...
Make it look cooler like that.
Now it looks kind of like...
I don't know what it looks like.
That's not nice.
I like that one.
I gotta change these though.
Yes!
Orange!
I love orange!
What about these?
Turn them black.
Black and orange.
That looks cool.
So we start with this.
We separate.
And we instantly start that.
The question is though...
Is it gonna be enough?
I think it is.
I think this is almost the exact same rocket I did.
That actually got us to orbit.
Is this orbiter one still?
It's iterating on it.
Save it.
That one.
This one.
Bup, bup, bup.
Looks good.
Let's go!
No casualties yet, by the way.
Just wanna, you know, put that out there.
Speed.
Sass.
And...
Liftoff!
We have liftoff!
What the hell's going on there?
Why does it look like that?
What the hell is that?
Is that a bug with the new thing I installed with the restock shit?
Could be.
But in any case, we have liftoff.
We're gonna separate this.
It's gonna fall in the ocean.
I don't even know what's happening over there.
Look at that.
That's weird.
Interesting.
Jebediah?
Do you believe we're gonna get to orbit?
Yes.
That's the spirit!
Now watch.
I'm gonna start turning now.
I do have a little bit of authority here.
Oh, that's not a lot.
Nevermind.
I don't have a lot.
As soon as I...
Separate, though, we're gonna have ultimate authority.
There we go.
And now we start turning more aggressively.
Kinda wanna...
How much can I actually turn without things getting out of hand?
Whoa.
Whoa, that doesn't look good.
Oy, shit.
Let's have a look.
I wish I wouldn't have to turn the map around every time I wanna look.
Okay.
I'm gonna burn exactly along our vector now.
We can get a little higher.
Dude, there's no way we have enough.
Stop.
Maybe.
Maybe it's actually fine.
This may not be enough.
Okay.
Get ready.
Let's speed up a bit.
Yeah, this is definitely more, sort of...
Less steep.
I think that's good.
We're not gonna have enough fuel.
I think we can start burning now.
But it's not gonna be enough, I don't think.
I hate that I'm solving the same problem as I did last time.
I can't believe I don't know how to get to orbit now.
Go!
Now we're losing fuel so fast!
It's not happening.
Is it?
Is it happening?
Actually, wait, wait.
Wait a bit more.
Let's wait until we're at the very top of the top of the tip.
There we go.
Now.
Burn!
Burn, you motherfucker!
Ah, Jebediah!
Ah, you motherfucker!
It's even worse than last time!
I hate you!
What is wrong with you?
Look at him.
It's your fault, Jeb.
You did this.
Okay, no use crying over... We need to drastically change this rocket.
Do that.
Turn it around.
Boom.
And then... Maximum speed.
We're falling all the way down.
Let's not kill ourselves here.
Gotta be a little careful.
Okay.
Oh, it automatically slowed down just now.
Oh, okay, that's actually kind of nice.
So it automatically slows down when you hit the atmosphere.
Very nice.
I'm gonna speed up even more, because we've done this a million times.
We know how this works by now.
Oh!
Holy God!
Oh my God!
You don't want to control the vessel when it's...
Uh... What do you call it?
When you have time warp on.
Because the reaction is crazy.
Yeah, okay.
Don't touch the time controls, man.
Not at this stage.
That's too dangerous.
Damn.
Haha, look at that!
I love this.
It looks so cool.
Again, we're landing on the dark side of the planet.
Whoa.
Okay, that was... that was... I mean...
The thing is, though, we're getting quite good at suborbital flights.
It's, like, not even a problem anymore, you know?
This is easy.
Next parachute.
I wish I could time warp even faster right now.
This is just another, uh... day at the office for Jeb here.
He's getting pretty good at this.
But we are burning money!
Like, the cash reserves are...
draining fast, you know?
We need to start to see some results here.
What contracts do I have?
Just orbiting!
We just... we gotta get to orbit, man.
We really do.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
I know this.
I think I just need to not suck as much.
I feel like my... my angle is bad.
The way I come up through the atmosphere.
I think I start to turn a little too early, so that's such that, you know, I expose more surface area, and I slow down through the atmosphere.
Or we add more boosters.
I actually like that.
I like adding...
Let's add more boosters.
Definitely.
That's the solution.
Okay, let's see if we can, uh, get some readings on...
Wait, are we gonna flood the tanks here?
Okay, I mean...
I can... I cannot see the thing.
Oh, we got it.
Hey!
The engineers hadn't planned on water, so the numbers have all washed off the thermometer, making it unreadable.
I guess it's still science.
Mystery goo.
Let's see what happens to the goo.
The goo escapes into the water!
Hey, we get science out of it.
Do we not have any more, uh...
There we go.
Pressure data.
The barometer reading isn't very interesting, so you look out the window and watch the waves instead.
I guess this is valuable data.
Close it.
Crew report.
Nothing new here.
All right, let's, uh, let's recover.
I mean, the good news is we're getting science out of this and experience.
Not actual experience in terms of, you know, the Kerbal earning experience, but I'm getting experience.
Um, right.
Okay.
So let's...
Let's actually really go back to the drawing board on this.
What is the current problem?
We just don't have enough fuel.
That's the problem.
So we have 3,600 delta V right now.
Let's just see if we can pump those numbers up.
What happens if I add this instead?
It becomes a little less.
Okay.
Right.
And let me see here.
Thrust-to-weight ratio of almost 3.
But with this one, it is pretty much the same.
Which means we actually can afford to add way more fuel tanks.
Let's say we add 3 more.
Ah!
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Is this a good idea?
Now we have 4,000 delta V.
Oh, wait.
This is the one I need to look at.
1.36 Thrust-to-weight ratio.
Oh, my God.
We're not going to have a lot of control authority on this.
That's the problem.
I feel like this is not the solution to, um...
Let's try and drastically switch things up.
We're trying something new.
Throw all this away.
This is the one that is going to burn at the top of the parabola.
Okay?
Now, instead...
Um...
Let me see.
What if we were to...
Hmm.
How did I do this last time, man?
I'm losing my mind.
How the hell did I do this?
We definitely want that.
And then we do...
Hey, what a...
Nah, you know what?
I actually...
I think I like, uh...
I like the idea of just adding more.
Just add more.
Like this.
And then we just have to sort of try and turn it anyway.
So wait, we have...
Thrust-to-weight ratio of 1.6.
What if I were to put a swivel in there like a little naughty boy?
1.4.
Okay, I mean...
1.5 actually.
Uh, we can do this.
I feel okay with this.
I do.
This may be it.
Or we do three stages instead of two.
That's also an option.
You know what?
I like that option.
We're doing it.
Don't think about it.
Just do it.
Put this guy there.
And...
Another decoupler.
Right?
And we add a little bit more.
It's gonna be like 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 into 3, into 2.
I like it.
This will be successful.
Let's add some colors to this.
So we can distinguish them easily.
These will be orange.
Okay, wait a minute.
Why is it...
Now does it say I have very low...
Oh, is it because I'm...
There we go.
This one and then that one together.
All together now.
But look at this.
I mean, this is like less delta V than the idea I had before.
So if I get rid of this...
Take this away.
This is better.
Apparently.
This is way too many.
Bro, I'm so confused.
This game is hard, man.
Why is...
Why is it so hard?
Hmm.
I mean, now we have control, at least.
Guys, I believe.
This is the one.
I just need to not suck.
Are you ready?
I got this.
We're gonna start with this.
We're gonna add some fins to this.
Four fins.
Not only that, we're gonna add more.
We're gonna add four fins to both stages.
So that when we separate the first, we're gonna have more...
Uh...
Stability.
Right?
Like that.
So this one goes off.
Bop, bop.
Let me actually turn this...
Gray.
These two.
That one.
Wait, wait.
Do we have an issue here?
We don't have an issue.
This is actually great.
Let me try one more fuel tank.
For good measure.
I like it, actually!
I like it.
Me like.
Save it!
This is the one.
Wait!
I'm an idiot!
This is what I did last time!
I got rid of this.
But maybe I need it.
We keep it.
I believe in the...
Craft is too many parts?
Oh.
Well, fuck these then.
Save.
Whatever.
This is gonna go to orbit now.
Are you ready?
Hold on.
Can I...
Uh...
I'm gonna fast forward here.
Whoa!
Jesus Christus!
Okay, that was a fast forward there.
I just wanted it to be day.
That's all.
We can't launch during the night.
I can't focus.
Okay, here we go.
You ready?
Speed.
Sass.
Boom.
Ooh!
We're a chongy boy!
This may be a bad rocket.
Oh god.
The swivel is weak.
It's a weak boy.
This may not be the best weather to launch in, but it's fine.
It's okay.
Okay.
Maybe.
I'm gonna start turning when we're at 5,000-ish meters.
Maybe I'll start turning a little bit now.
Just, like, slightly, you know?
Because our vector is pointing slightly left, which is not good for me.
Don't like that.
Make it point, like, straight up at least.
There we go.
Breaking through the clouds.
Oh my god.
We're so wobbly!
It's a wobbly rocket.
Whoa.
Look at that, man.
Okay.
Start turning.
Another cloud layer.
Trust the instruments.
Time for separation.
And...
Now!
Turn more.
Not too...
Whoa!
I'm losing control.
Jebediah, you bastard.
You bastard.
Dude, we cannot get to orbit with this.
There is no fucking way.
There is no way.
Stop.
Let's see.
Oh, it's not even that high.
Keep burning.
What the hell did I do last time?
How did I do this?
Hey, we're in orbit now.
Look, it says orbit.
We did it.
If only.
That may be too high now.
Aw, fuck.
We're not gonna make it, man.
We're not gonna make it again.
Shitballs!
Can we speed up even more?
Can't go more than four.
I think I'm going way too peaky, you know?
Okay.
Let's just start.
Let's see.
Honestly, I think I got it.
I just need to not suck at the...
At the turn.
At the burn and turn, you know?
Okay, let's start burning now.
Bro, we're not gonna get to whatever speed we need here.
There's no way.
Look at this.
We have 500 delta V left.
It's not happening.
So I guess I'm just gonna...
We're gonna cut it there.
Cut our losses.
We're gonna separate this bastard right now.
And we're gonna go home with a tail between our legs.
And it's not gonna feel good.
It is what it is.
Goodbye, booster.
Well, not technically a booster.
First stage.
Second stage.
Whoa!
Oh, the fuck?
Dude, SAS is insane.
Like, game-changing.
Oh, now I can go faster.
I guess the higher up you are, the faster you can go.
Now it's slowed down automatically.
Okay.
Once again, going back home with no orbit.
It's the turn, man!
I'm not doing the turn right.
I'm just trying to understand how I did this last time.
You know?
Like, how did I even manage?
Parachute.
In fact, I'm gonna launch the other parachute a little later than usual.
I'm gonna be a little daring just to get down faster.
Let's see how naughty I can be.
I mean, we're going super slow already, right?
So...
Hey, at least we're optimizing every single step of the way for these suborbital flights.
Down to the point where we even go down faster to the surface, you know, so we can get home for lunch.
Jebediah, maybe we have to replace you.
We may have to bring in someone else.
In fact, I think that's the problem right now.
It's actually Jebediah.
He's not doing it right.
He is the one that is causing issues here for everyone.
Hmm...
No, no.
We're gonna keep fucking going here.
We're going to orbit right now.
This is the orbit right now, brother.
It's happening.
Okay, so...
It feels to me like we need to go faster at the start.
We were way too slow.
That's why boosters exist, bro.
Boost me up, Scotty.
And we...
And you know what?
We're gonna take smaller ones and put them on the side now instead of these big ones.
This is the innovation.
Like that.
Looks like a penis.
But it's okay.
3.42 thrust to weight.
That is insane.
So this goes off...
And we hit...
Oh, did I actually do a three stage the way...
when I got to orbit?
Maybe I did that, actually.
Maybe that's what I did.
You know what?
Since we have so much TWR...
Let's go fucking crazy.
Hello?
4,200!
Okay.
If I don't go orbit now...
I will go out back and I will make myself a sandwich...
and eat it.
That's right.
That's the punishment.
So we do these two.
Separate.
We're running down.
Look, our money is dwindling.
We are at that stage just like SpaceX very early on during that company where they pretty much were broke and they had like one launch to bring home the bacon, you know?
We're almost at that stage right now.
We cannot fuck this up.
This is it.
Oh, God!
Let me see.
So these two...
These three go off.
And thrust to weight of three.
That's actually amazing.
Which means we're gonna go...
Maybe that's too much, actually.
Think about it.
Let's do three of these.
Oh, my God.
It looks sick, too.
Even more delta V.
Oh, wait.
It's higher now.
I thought maybe the added mass would be...
Hmm.
Um.
Wait.
I need to think.
We're gonna go too fast.
Yo!
This is the solution.
Oh, my God.
Okay.
So now we have a...
2.7...
Let me actually go even further down.
This sounds crazy, but...
There's an idea behind this, okay?
The idea...
Listen.
The reason I'm bringing down the thrust to weight ratio...
Is that I don't wanna go up too fast.
So that I don't manage to turn in time.
The problem here, though, is we're gonna be burning for way longer.
Which means we're gonna have less control authority for a long time.
So that's also a problem.
But maybe if I turn really hard...
Maybe it'll work.
You know?
These two...
Bro, I think this is it.
I think we got it.
I'm also being...
Look at this shadow, though.
I'm being stubborn bringing this science module with me here.
You know?
Because I wanna do that in orbit.
I'm trying to do two birds with one scone.
So...
I'm being a little greedy.
I understand.
Let's try this.
We have limited the thrust.
Let's see if it'll pay off.
Okay.
Speed.
Sass.
Go!
We're gonna slightly turn already.
It sounds crazy, I know.
But trust me.
If we put the turn in early...
Maybe it'll...
Keep turning automatically as time goes on.
Nah, I mean...
It's gonna balance around the shape of it.
Okay.
Let's start to...
I'm turning hard right now as much as I can, I guess.
Which is not a lot.
I'm really trying.
Dude, this is gonna...
Oh, shit.
Look at our speed.
Oh!
Oh, no.
Actually, it may be fine.
Oh, this is a...
Oh, no.
Oh, shit.
Uh-oh.
Dude, we're gonna start fall down again.
Oh, my God.
I can't believe it.
One of the main...
Objectives of a rocket is to go up.
And we're about to drop.
Oh, no.
Oh, look at our vector.
See ya, vector.
Oh, we're speeding up.
We're speeding up.
Oh, wait.
We're speeding up because we're falling down.
Oh, shit.
No.
No!
Separation!
Okay, you know what?
Jebediah!
Your days are done.
You're done.
No more flying for you.
You are done.
I've had it with your shit.
That's it.
Deploy the chute.
You're going home.
Let's go.
Dude, how am I fucking...
Oh, you know what it is?
It's not even my fault, actually.
Oh...
It's not even me.
I put it on hard.
It's probably harder to get to orbit.
That's what it is, man.
That's the explanation.
Ah, that's how I did it last time.
I had it on easy.
Cheers.
Oh, my God.
I can't believe...
Hey, look at this.
We're landing right next to home.
That's kind of nice.
Jeb, you can walk home.
Helicopter pickup?
Nuh-uh.
Not this time.
You're going to have to swim.
That's your penance.
For what you've done here today.
How could you have decided...
To limit the thrust like that, huh?
Rookie moves.
My friend.
Recover the vessel.
Okay, okay, okay.
Listen.
We're not going to fuck around no more.
This is it.
This is the rocket.
Okay, we didn't lose that much money.
We're recovering the parts, right?
So, it's actually fine.
Listen.
Thrust limiter.
60%.
And...
I don't trust this...
Guy right here anymore.
You're gone.
We want a pilot.
We want Valentina.
She's going to show you how to do things.
You ready?
Save.
Valentina's going to do it in one shot.
Watch this.
Great decision, Valentina, to put the thrust limiter on 60.
I don't know what Jet was thinking on 30.
She's excited.
Because she knows she's right.
Oh, yeah.
It feels good.
It's beautiful.
It's fine.
We're getting higher up.
We're going to reverse.
Watch.
According to her calculations, it should happen approximately...
Eight seconds.
Three.
Two.
One.
Now.
Ish.
Start turning.
Slightly, if we can.
The built-in reaction wheels are not powerful enough.
Fuck.
No.
Why am I regressing?
What's happening?
Now watch.
Here we go.
Valentina has made the calculations.
Turn it.
Come on, girl.
You got this.
Come on.
Oh, my God.
Oh, it's going to be close.
Come on.
Oh, no.
It's not going to be enough.
Valentina, I trusted you.
I trusted you.
Oh.
Shit.
We still have some fuel.
It's happening.
Oh, my God.
We're going to burn here.
We're done.
Valentina.
Showing us how it's done.
Look at her.
Look how excited she is.
Wow.
You did it.
Oh, my God.
Oh, ho, ho, ho, ho, ho, ho, ho, ho.
Okay.
Let's now time forward until we are on the other side.
We want to increase our periapses now.
A little more.
That's it.
Now.
We want to turn prograde.
We're not going to need a lot.
It's going to be very slight here.
There we go.
S-A-S.
Boom.
In fact.
Burn.
There it is.
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
Never doubt, Valentina.
Okay.
Now we got to get home.
That's easy.
That's actually very easy.
We just turn our butt the other way.
And we release a tiny fart.
And I do mean tiny.
In fact, I'm going to make it home with fuel to spare.
Just to, you know, rub it in Jeb's face.
Like this.
Ready?
That's it.
That's all we need.
Okay, wait.
Maybe we need more.
That's all we need.
Look.
In fact, we could need a little less.
I need to go a little faster.
I don't want to land on on the dark side.
So we're going to point this way now.
This music is just perfect for being in space, isn't it?
All right.
We should go even further.
That's enough.
We're going to slow down in the atmosphere.
I'm going to separate.
Fuck!
I should have done the experiments while in orbit.
It's probably got a...
It should...
It would have gotten us a lot, you know?
Oh, man.
That's too bad.
That's okay.
Valentina is not, you know, a science expert.
She's good at flying the craft.
She's a proper pilot.
That's all that matters right now.
Let's not let this little unfortunate incident overshadow the success here.
Nothing to gain from that.
Let's just close that up.
I was too overwhelmed by the, uh...
By the success here that I totally forgot about the science, you know?
Okay.
Let's speed this up.
Uh, this button here.
Whee!
Let me remove this.
Whoa!
What's that?
Eve!
Is it purple?
I mean, the text is purple.
Look at the planet.
It looks slightly purple.
Oh, wait.
We're not actually going to end up on the...
On the light side, are we?
Bring it on.
Valentina has learned from...
Jebediah's suborbital adventures.
It's very sensitive.
Is that a lightning strike?
Oh, maybe we are!
This is a very shallow angle.
Oh, my God.
That is freaking glorious, dude!
Look at that!
Ho, ho, ho, ho!
Oh!
Damn!
That's pretty.
Notice how we're slowing down more, so we have a more steep angle into the atmosphere than our debris up here, which has probably aligned itself to be more like a missile.
So it's cleaving the air more efficiently, a.k.a.
it's higher up than we are.
I love that that all makes sense.
You know?
I can't get enough of this view.
Hey, wait.
We can probably control it from here.
Look at this!
Haha!
The nav ball is working!
That's fantastic.
Main chutes...
No.
Drogue chutes.
Followed by main chutes.
And we actually did it.
Nobody has died yet.
This is the most important thing.
You have to remember this.
Science will be done in time.
As long as we don't lose anybody in the process, I consider that a win.
Any landing you can walk away from, right, is a good one.
Now, what are these white thingies on the ground there?
I guess I technically could walk over there.
But I don't know if I should.
Maybe they're just little plants or something.
Maybe we can do some science while we're floating here?
Nothing there.
What about temperature?
Hey!
As you perform temperature scans over the grasslands, you take care not to hit any trees.
Well, we don't really have any control over this.
unless we can somehow affect the parachutes somehow.
Pull on them in one way or the other.
I wonder if real, uh, capsules have that capability with parachutes.
You know, slightly pulling on one of these.
Steer it a little bit.
Maybe.
What's this?
Warp to sunrise!
Oh, that's a nice button!
Double time mode.
Okay.
What is that?
Oh, no alarms.
Board action group.
Okay.
Uh, well, we made it, man!
Finally!
That took a while.
We got some more science, too.
But the most important...
Oh!
She leveled up!
She had a little star.
Uh, let me see this.
Astronaut complex.
Man, look.
Valentina does one mission, gets promoted.
Jebediah, six or seven missions, is still a rookie.
What does that tell you?
This guy is stupid.
I mean, his stupidity is half.
Valentina's stupidity is lower.
And it makes sense.
Unless it got lower because she just got promoted.
Maybe that's actually what happened.
I'm not sure.
Prograde, retrograde hold.
Full vessel control without comnet access.
Wait, stability assist?
Orbit around carbon two.
Flight at carbon one?
There's no way he has more than one flight at carbon.
That's not right.
Wait a minute.
So wait.
Engineer, increase resource converter efficiency, increase drill efficiency, deployed power generation units?
And a scientist.
Missile science return 100%.
Part science return 100%.
Okay.
Reset experiments.
But am I not able to do this already?
Run experiments from EVA?
Why is that good?
Science generation rate.
25%.
Okay, so we get more science with Bob, or what?
We generate more science?
Oh, look at his stupidity.
It's very low.
I guess he's smart.
He's smart kerbal.
All right, nice.
We do need to get a little bit more science so we can unlock more parts, though.
And let's see what else is on the menu here.
Explore the moon!
Straight up after that?
We go straight to this?
Okay.
As a consequence of a somewhat worse than average accident at Kirbin World First's Record Keeping Society, we've been forced to look for some outside help.
We still have unchecked items on our list of records to break and would like to change that.
So this is where you come in.
In the grand scheme of things, we know very little about the moon.
Let's see if we can explore it a bit further.
Today's your lucky day.
Simply head to the moon and pass by it.
Easy as pie.
No risk at all.
Now sign this waiver.
Sometimes science throws a curveball and we need to ask the hard questions.
And by we, we mean you.
Head to the moon.
It would be somewhat disconcerting if all of our missions to the moon were one-way trips.
Bring one back to Kirbin.
Yeah, that one is a given.
Dude, look at all these monies we're gonna get!
Gather scientific data from the moon!
I love that!
Return to Kirbin from a flyby of the moon.
Oh my god.
Dude.
This is actually not even that hard if you think about it.
Once you're in space, whatever fuel you have left is gonna take you way farther.
You know?
Way!
Or the thing that costs way more fuel than anything else is escaping the gravity of the earth, right?
Or in this case, Kirbin.
This is actually not gonna be too hard, I think.
I think we can do it.
Let's see what else we can do here, though.
Test this in flight over Kirbin.
How?
Oh man, that sounds kinda difficult, though.
So you would have to be at this exact height and speed, and then you activate a stage where this one...
Oh, that sounds crazy.
How are you even gonna do that?
Test the thumper solid fuel booster at the launch site.
That's easy.
But it's also almost not worth doing.
Which kind of...
Nuts.
Obviously, we take this.
Boom.
Accept it.
I accept your challenge.
We're going to the moon.
And to get there...
Let me have a look in here first, actually.
This is the rocket that did it.
It's ugly as hell.
I actually hate it.
Ew!
Ew.
Orbiter won.
Success now.
It worked.
Okay.
Let's see here.
We're going straight to the moon.
We also have this.
Oh, wait.
I forgot about this.
I need to read...
I need to read this again.
Uh...
Created the experiment storage unit to help Cribblenauts bring their valuable science back to Kerbin while avoiding the hazards of re-entry.
How do you avoid the hazards?
Tolerance.
Very high pressure tolerance.
I guess it's the same, I guess.
It has a higher impact tolerance.
It can handle way higher temperatures.
Oh, that's why, I guess.
It's kind of big.
Let me see.
Alright.
Definitely don't want to put that on the outside like this.
You want to put it somewhere smart.
So, Science Junior.
Self-contained laboratory.
Oh my god, it's huge.
Wait.
I guess you would
open doors.
Oh, shit.
Aha!
Look at all this!
All kinds of experiments in space.
They have a toast and a little alien in a tube.
Watching plants grow with oranges on it.
That's cute.
Wait.
Can we not just hold on?
Get rid of this stuff.
I'm gonna I'm gonna just do this.
Get rid of this.
Don't even need that.
I don't intend to launch.
I intend to just try this.
Let's bring in Bob.
He has 25% extra science generation.
I wanna see how this works.
And it's super cheap too because we almost didn't buy any parts.
Um.
Conduct material study.
The materials show little signs of change.
Though one of the samples appears to be judging you silently.
I guess because we didn't need to go on a rocket to test this because we're literally just on the surface.
Okay, it's just another science experiment.
So wait.
Uh.
I'm confused though.
Did we get more?
Because we have Bob?
You feel compelled to stare at the sky.
It's very cloudy.
Um.
Let me do this.
Collect data.
Removing the experiment data will render this module inoperable.
Restoring functionality will require a scientist.
So I have the science?
Oh.
Review stored data.
Media restored.
Module is operational again.
Wait a second.
Does that mean I can conduct this test at different stages of the journey?
With a scientist?
Um.
I wish I could get back up here.
Like, hello?
Let me get in the vessel.
Ah!
Bob.
Come on.
Wait, let me do this.
Conduct another study?
You think this experiment is rather superfluous?
So wait, I can just keep doing this?
Collect data?
Did I just discover a fucking loophole?
There's no way.
Hold on.
How do I...
Can I not recover myself?
Oh, climb?
Oh.
Oh, Bob!
How did you do that?
Ah.
Grab.
Hey!
Experiments you have collected cannot be stored on this Mark 1 command pod.
Are you sure you want to...
Wait, why not?
Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Store experiments.
Material study from Launchpad already stored in this module.
Take data.
Store.
Wait, what?
Is it because of duplicate?
Review stored data.
EVA report.
Oh, okay.
Yeah, okay, I see.
So you can't just...
I see.
I had duplicates, that's why.
It makes sense.
Otherwise, it would have been kind of a crazy loophole.
And even if that was a loophole, I wouldn't have abused it, you know?
That would be terrible.
Okay, cool.
So basically, we just need to do this a couple times.
I like it.
It's time for some science missions.
Smaller science missions.
We need a parachute for that.
We're not gonna need a heat shield for this one.
We do need a little...
flea solid booster, maybe.
And then, of course, we do the science...
junior.
Like that.
Hopefully, this is enough.
Let's play it safe.
And do a decoupler here.
Like that.
And...
Ah, you know what, actually?
This is like a science module.
Isn't that gonna be fragile?
Let's add a...
heat shield.
Just because, you know?
I think it's good practice.
So we start by doing that.
And then we...
disconnect after.
I don't want this anymore.
Boom, boom, boom.
Boom, boom.
And...
Bob.
So wait.
If I do Bob, we're not gonna be able to do...
the stability assist, right?
Do we need to, though?
What is the point of Bob, though?
Do I need Bob right now?
I guess he can reset it.
But we can't overwrite.
Ah!
But if we get to multiple areas, we can store different experiments.
So...
I guess that makes sense.
Yeah, that's fine.
Can he actually fly, though?
Wait a minute.
Will it even launch?
He's not a pilot, technically, right?
So I'm not actually sure I can even control this.
In any case, we have a parachute ready to go.
Orbiter 1 has no operational SAS modules and no pilots aboard.
Cannot engage.
Makes sense.
Okay, so we can definitely activate the rocket.
I'm gonna slightly turn towards the ocean here.
Disconnect.
Maybe the heat shield was a bit overkill here.
But better be safe than sorry, right?
Parachute.
Maybe I can perform an experiment now?
The less resilient samples appear to have splattered around the interior, forming new and interesting color combinations.
Yeah, how is everything not just...
10.5 science?
Brother, we're rich?
Holy shit, dude.
Wow.
I mean, this is it.
We made it.
Speed that up.
Oh my god.
Bob is getting a little sick from this, I think.
Maybe we need some SAS.
Oh, we can't.
Right.
Let me manually try and...
That's...
There we go.
Should I close this before we...
hit the water?
Yo, we're gonna try and reset it and get experiments from the water too.
Because we have Bob.
Speed up the time.
I am...
Dude, I am fucking loving this game so far.
Just thinking about the...
future of going to the moon.
And like all the other things.
Holy shit, bro.
Slow down.
Oh, didn't mean to open map.
Oy.
Look at that.
It's like a little pill.
Okay.
Uh...
EVA?
What if I fall in the water?
Well, you can actually reach from here.
Oh.
Collect data?
Restore?
Conduct material study?
Now watch.
We're gonna be in water now, so...
As you open the material space...
A seagull flies out and poops on your hand.
It seems you can never escape the reach of the beach.
Ah, shit.
Ah, well.
Worth it for the science, right?
Then we do...
Close doors.
Enter.
And we should have...
Wait.
Okay, so this is while flying.
And then here...
Oh my god.
Dude, scientists...
Are crazy.
That's like 16 science.
Right there.
Oh!
Amazing.
Now we can afford more.
Oh god, what do I want?
I guess I want this, right?
We want to go into more rockets.
What is this?
Let's see.
Mark 1 crew cabin.
A cozy passenger cabin derived from a business jet and upgraded for use in spacecraft.
Strut connector.
Highly regarded by many spacecraft engineers as they help in constructing more stable spacecraft.
Once both sides are connected, a structural beam is created to link both ends.
Allowing for sturdier and heavier construction.
Whoa.
What's that?
Launch stability enhancer?
Flag.
Engine plate.
Inspired by an upside down birthday cake.
But with added shrouds for windy days.
For clustering multiple small engines on small tanks.
Huh.
Okay.
What about this?
Flight control.
I feel like I need this.
Like...
I need control.
But that's a lot of science to spend on not a lot of things here.
Wait.
Crew capacity too?
Yo.
So we bring a pilot and a scientist.
Oh, I'm so torn.
There's also this.
This is only 18, but if I buy this, I can't buy this.
Dude, I want more engines.
I want engines.
We're getting this.
And then the next thing I buy is this one, I think.
Because I do want bigger control surfaces, you know?
For more control.
Aerodynamic nose cone.
Aerodynamic, lightweight, and mostly non-explosive.
As a reminder to all personnel operating nearby, this part is really sharp.
And it'd probably hurt if you fell on it.
This could have helped, assuming it's the right size, to prevent the flat surfaces, you know, on the extra tanks you put on.
Or boosters.
But dude, it's gonna be easy to get this because I just bring the science module up in space and it's probably gonna give us a shit ton of science.
I think we're set for science for a small bit here, at least.
Let's see.
Contracts?
What do we have?
Oh yeah, explore the moon, right.
Should we try and make a moon mission?
Is this too crazy already?
Am I going a little nuts?
You know what?
I think we should collect a little bit of science before we do that.
So meaning, go to orbit.
Now that we're pros at that, we can grab science with the science junior.
Is there a science senior?
Maybe.
I think this is a good start though.
This is like the base setup.
Let's put on some chutes.
There's also these.
That's like a firework launcher.
I don't want that.
Ew.
This is like the standard setup.
Get rid of that crap.
Do that.
That's the main sort of setup there.
Oh, wait a minute.
We never did get the science from orbit, did we?
With the old setup here.
So we're gonna...
Let me actually open here.
Don't save.
We're going to grab the orbiter one.
That one.
We're gonna remove this crap.
We're gonna attach the science junior up here.
Actually, we're gonna grab it from there.
Science is here.
There's also this thing.
I'll have to experiment with that.
But right now, I just want to grab science.
Heat shield.
Yeah, you want to protect the fragile science experiments.
This is like a heavy science setup here.
Okay, let's see.
Oh, we got new stuff here.
That's right.
Wait, what's this?
A fuel tank.
Wait, that's a massive one.
Fuel tank adapter.
These fuel-filled adapters come in a variety of sizes for connecting larger and smaller tanks.
Oh, we're gonna make it like an outline.
I want that.
Engines.
It's a new one.
Oh, look how cute it is.
Let me see here.
Yeah, this one is way more efficient in vacuum.
I figured it would be for something when you're already in space.
Thud.
Oh, that's...
That's nice.
Yo, that looks kinda sick.
Look.
Actually, I want to put it further down, if anything.
Oh, I guess I can't put it on here, because it's like a...
Actually, why can't I do that?
What am I doing?
Oh!
Wait, wait, wait.
I have an idea.
We're gonna...
We're actually gonna make a three-stage rocket for this.
We are gonna have...
Let me put the small engine here.
This is like the last one, right?
We're not gonna be escaping any atmosphere there.
Put this one here.
Then we have the middle stage.
Hmm.
The thing is, though, we're adding, like, a lot of shit to this.
It's gonna make it harder to get into orbit.
But it's okay.
Let's now add another one.
And then we go crazy and add a...
Thumper.
Wait, we have terrible delta-v here, though.
Is that because it's wrongly configured?
I think it is because of that.
4,200!
Okay, okay, that's good, that's good, that's good.
So these two get activated.
Next stage, nice.
This one.
That one, nice.
Then we have...
That one, yes.
And then these two, perfect.
Ooh!
The problem here is, though...
No, we are gonna have control.
Because we have a swivel in there.
Right?
That's a swivel?
Yeah, nice.
Okay, so...
1.67.
TWR is actually perfect for the first stage here.
It's not too much, it's not too little.
It's right on the money.
This one goes there.
I do want to separate these immediately.
Dude, I need to go take a piss real bad.
And then we're going...
Orbit?
With...
And you know what?
This time?
It's Jebediah, because he has now learned from Valentina.
She has taught him in the classroom.
He's got all the basics down.
Let's see if he can do it.
I'll be back in like, one minute.
Alright, here we go.
On the way back, I took a handful of candy and jammed it in my mouth.
I felt like a giant pig.
But now I have fuel.
I'm so ready for this, dude.
Are you ready?
I think we're set.
This is gonna be...
Orbiter 2.
We go high and stay high.
And do science.
Save it.
This is the rocket, dude.
I was also thinking, while I was taking a leak...
Adding these little...
Control surfaces down here.
Where are they?
These ones.
The basic fin.
It's actually gonna make it harder to turn the rocket.
Because if you think about it logically, when you have these, and they can't actually move...
Like, you can't control these.
These are just fins.
You know, when you turn the rocket, the air is gonna work against you.
It's gonna wanna try and keep the rocket straight.
That's the whole point of it.
That's why you add fins to, like, an arrow.
You know?
So we're not gonna add fins.
Here we go.
Okay.
Jebediah, you glorious bastard.
Let's see if you can redeem yourself here.
Speed.
Sass.
We're off.
On a mission to investigate Science Junior in orbit around Kerbin.
Godspeed.
What the hell is that back there?
Look at that.
Is that a hole in the ground?
What is that?
It's black.
Huh.
No idea.
Doesn't matter.
What interests me is in space, not on the ground.
Okay, get ready for stage separation.
Boom.
Oh yeah, we have three stages on this one.
Oi!
This is gonna be sick.
I'm gonna turn very slightly, not too much.
Jebediah, remember what Valentina taught you.
Okay?
Remember.
Don't be a dumbass.
You got this.
I know you were paying attention in that classroom, weren't you?
I'm gonna turn even more now.
We're gonna, like, slightly turn more.
Like this.
Let me see where we are.
What's it looking like?
Okay, okay.
Keep going.
It's good.
It's good, I think.
Maybe.
Maybe a little more turn here.
And that's it.
That's not very high, is it?
Separate.
Godspeed, booster.
Let's see what this little guy can do.
And we're gonna wait until we're higher up here.
And speed up just slightly.
Oh, actually, this is looking pretty fucking good.
Someone's been paying attention when Valentina was speaking.
Okay, I think it's time.
Point horizontal.
Let's go.
Oh my god, it's so slow.
Oh shit, I should have started burning way earlier.
Jebediah, you got this.
Uh-oh.
We should have started burning way earlier.
Look at how long this lasts.
This is so efficiency.
I mean efficient.
I don't know if I should be burning exactly prograde right now, or horizontal to the ground.
I think horizontal to the ground is gonna make it a little more circular in the end.
It's hard to say.
I'm just gonna stick to my current burn.
Dude, look how much fuel...
This lasts a long time.
Lesson learned, though.
With this little engine here, you wanna burn earlier.
Okay, it's happening.
Raise that periapsis.
Yeah.
There it is.
A little more.
Stop.
And we still have a lot of fuel left.
I don't think we're in orbit.
Are we?
Maybe we're in orbit.
Oh no, we definitely are.
Because this is the low...
This is like periapsis area here, and we are already...
out of the atmosphere.
There's the moon!
Dude, let's go to the moon right now.
We probably can't.
Okay, so now...
Since we're in orbit...
Let's do some experiments.
A service bay.
Let's have a look inside.
Too hot thermometer.
As usual, the thermometer here is unreliable.
You write down its reading anyway for the scientists back at KSC.
In space near Kerbin.
I actually thought it would say in orbit.
I guess no science there.
What about the mystery goo?
Really?
It seems to have clumped into a sphere.
Man, that's not worth it.
Reset that.
What about the press mat?
What?
Okay, what's happening here?
What about the science junior?
Conduct material study.
Save me.
15 science!
That's what I'm talking about!
The microgravity has greatly affected the growth of crystalline structures.
I guess these ones here.
Those objects are also flying around the bay in a very messy but fascinating way.
Okay, we should probably close the doors then.
We don't want those to fall out.
It's horrible.
Close that.
I guess we don't need to close this because, I mean, there's no air right now.
We're good.
So, here's the plan.
I'm actually going to burn a little more.
I'm going to turn prograde.
We're going to get a little higher.
I don't want to be near Kerbin.
I want to be far away from Kerbin.
We still have lots of fuel left.
Fuck!
What if we get stuck in orbit?
I got to be really careful here.
I'm actually going to leave this as emergency backup fuel now.
So pretty.
Okay.
Let's fast forward a little bit here.
I just want to be in a different sort of area and height when it comes to doing experiments.
Oh, man.
Look.
Man, this game is producing some views.
And there it's gone.
Let's go faster.
Here come the planets into view!
Look at that!
Sunrise.
Hold on.
We need to.
Orient this.
Where's the...
Earth?
Okay.
So that's the plane of the solar system there.
A galaxy, even.
So as long as we just...
Turn this way.
That's the moon!
But it's not this side.
That I want to see.
It's this side.
Look.
It's getting smaller.
As we fly away.
Where are we in the orbit?
We're close to the...
Apwapses here.
It should be around here.
Let's go a little further until we reach that.
Right there.
Oh!
Look at that.
Dude!
Fuck me!
Oh!
Cheers!
That's just amazing.
What a view.
Okay.
Let's do some science now, shall we?
The goo.
There we go!
In space high above carbon.
The goo seems to...
Seems fine with being high over carbon.
Fantastic!
Okay.
Temperature scan.
Let's see what it says.
7.2 science.
Measuring the temperature of space appears to be quite impossible.
As there is no matter around to be either hot or cold.
Except the spacecraft and the thermometer itself.
This is probably going to give the R&D guy something to think about for a while.
True.
Ah, hell.
This is useless.
I have a feeling it's going to be useless quite a lot of times.
Tense!
Dude, we're going to be rich when we get home.
I kind of want to overwrite.
Oh, it's 15 though.
So this is space near Kerbin.
Wait.
Ah, but we can't reset it without a scientist.
Oh, man.
I want to bring another Kerbal with me up here.
Dang, dude.
I think I'm actually going to overwrite it though.
Because we are in a place right now that is more rare than just...
You know, low Earth orbit.
I'm going to reset it.
Conduct.
Moving.
22.5!
As you write down your lab report, you visually confirm that Kerbin's oceans do indeed make up the majority of its surface.
And there we get the answers to the question I had earlier.
It is a blue planet.
Incredible.
Just look at this.
And the moon back there.
Dang.
It's a time for a snack.
And the food box back there.
Hold on.
I want to actually control this from here.
Okay.
So we want to be burning retrograde right now.
We want to slow down.
That's prograde.
And we are approximately at apoapsis right now.
Which means we're going to reduce elevation of periapsis significantly with very little input.
There we go.
Ah!
When I click SIS, the little thing turns on down there.
That's cool.
You ready?
The orbit.
I think this is enough already.
6.5.
Ah, maybe not quite.
That does look very high above the surface.
I do want to end up on...
Not on the dark side, right?
So...
Let's burn a little more.
Okay.
Now that's what I'm talking about.
Maybe a little more.
There we go.
That should do it.
Maybe a bit more.
That's it.
We have done it.
Now...
I'm going to separate right now because I'm so sure of this.
Jebediah...
The Victory Lab is coming in.
Despite all your failures today...
You have indeed managed...
To surprise us all.
With the help of Valentina and her great advice in the classroom...
You have managed to reach orbit.
Not only that...
We've gotten quite far...
Away from the planet.
And look how excited you are.
Well deserved, friend.
Let's speed it up.
As we approach...
The blue marble.
Whoa.
It looks so crazy when you speed up like this.
Oh!
That's scary.
Let me turn around like this.
We actually have one more issue here.
We have to be careful.
We have not done a re-entry...
With something that looks like this.
Also, hold on.
How about we close these doors here?
Don't want the freaking...
Crystals or whatever and...
The toast in there to get too toasted.
Speed up more.
So we're still at like a hundred and...
Freaking...
Sixty...
Kilometers right now.
We should...
Have plenty of time...
Yeah, from this angle, it doesn't even look that bad, does it?
But from the other angle, it looks way more crazy.
Now we angle it this way.
Here we go.
Maybe a little more.
It's about...
Seventy...
Kilometers.
That's when we start to hit the atmosphere.
More.
Okay, let's slow down.
Get ready.
Here we go.
Oh, that's a crazy view.
Try and adjust it there.
This angle doesn't look good to me.
That looks better.
Wait, what was that?
Something just happened.
Is something overheating?
Whoa.
Protect the science experiments.
Oh, God.
Oh!
Oh, my God.
Oh, God.
Dude, it's overheating if I don't have the right angle.
Don't let the heat near it.
Oh, my God.
We're cooked.
Oh.
Shit.
Oh!
Fuck!
Jim and I, hold on!
The fucking heat shield is misaligned!
Oh, shit!
Hold on to your fucking green face on your ears.
Oh!
Oh, God!
Oh, shit!
Jim!
We're a missile!
The other way!
Turn around, you bastard!
We're not slowing down.
Oh, shit.
Fuck.
Sideways, sideways, sideways.
Stay sideways.
Slow down.
Slow the fuck down.
Jebediah.
This is what you've been practicing for.
Shit.
Oh, he will not turn around.
Fuck it.
Is my heat shield gone?
Heat shield fell off, bro.
Holy fuck.
Holy shit.
Wow.
Oh, God.
Oh, don't become a missile.
Don't do it.
Oh, no.
We're a missile.
This is bad.
Jebediah!
Oh, God.
That's right.
Wiggle back and forth.
Get that air resistance in.
Come on.
Slow the fuck down.
Parachute!
Yeah.
Come on.
Hold on.
Ugh.
Oh.
Oh, my God.
Main chute's deployed.
Holy crap.
Wow.
Dude, I thought we were cooked.
Look at him.
Calm as a cucumber.
Actually, he kind of looks like a cucumber.
That's the perfect saying for this situation.
Wow, man.
Hey, you know what?
We lost some science, but we got home safely.
That's all that matters.
Jesus Christ.
I had a feeling it would go bad with that configuration of...
But how do I bring it back?
Oh, maybe that's what the experimental storage unit is for.
Or the experiment storage tube, or whatever it's called.
You know the other one I can make?
That's probably what that's for, man.
Yeah.
Wow.
Jebediah, I can't believe you made it home.
And you know what?
It's not a failure at all, because we got a bunch of science.
This is not bad.
Okay, well...
Let's go home.
Wow.
28 science earned.
Oh, but it's not even enough to buy the next stage here of...
Science, I guess.
Or...
This needs 90?
Are you kidding me?
How on earth am I gonna...
Do that?
Maybe the answer is, maybe it's not on earth.
I can't believe I came home from that.
Is this even worth doing?
I feel like I should just go back up and do more science.
I need science.
We have a lot of money now, again.
164,000.
This is actually going pretty swimmingly.
What is this?
Let me actually take a look at this.
We have more stuff we can do, it seems.
Fundraising campaign.
Uh...
Yields funds for each one unit of reputation.
Okay, so it's like a market.
Yeah.
We can get better deals with our suppliers by taking up a more assertive stance on our negotiations with them.
You probably won't see this as a friendly move, but we can definitely have it our way if we press them.
So wait.
Is this something I should be doing?
5% of minimum vessel recovery?
I don't know what that means.
Bailout grant.
We lose reputation, but we gain funds.
Ah.
Can I...
Can I get...
Get science?
Takes 5% reputation gains.
Yields one science for each 2.5 reputation.
Ah.
Ah...
Takes 5% funds income.
Yields one science.
Oh.
I feel like I need science more than funds.
It costs 76,000 to set up.
Ooh, I don't know if I should do this.
This may not be a good idea.
Wait a minute.
I also need to check something.
So...
Okay.
It costs 450,000 to upgrade that.
What about the others?
Wait.
Patched conics visible in map.
Oh, shit!
So, conics are like, um...
Different...
So, if you take a conic and you slice it in different ways...
So, it's basically like different shapes of...
Of, like, orbits, right?
So, I wonder how that's gonna help.
What about this one?
Research science limit?
This costs 900,000...
Also, what is this space plane hangar?
Oh, right.
That's for making planes.
Do we even have parts for that?
I don't think I actually have any...
Parts for this.
Never mind that.
I don't wanna make planes.
I wanna make rockets.
Hey, Jebediah leveled up, too.
Neat.
Um...
Okay, let's just keep going.
We gotta make a simple...
I actually like the one we just had.
Orbiter 2.
The modification we're gonna make, though, is...
I will try...
This one, because I think this is what we need.
But how?
Do we put it in here?
It can't be on the outside like that.
Wait, hold on.
Also, hold on a minute.
Do we even need...
I'm gonna bring Bob for this.
Who needs SAS?
Not me.
He's gonna be resetting shit.
Actually, that's a bad idea.
Reentry is gonna be tough.
Reentry is actually kind of a bitch.
Yeah, we can't do that.
It's too risky.
Let's put this guy...
There.
And you know what?
We can actually do...
This.
And we can also turn it, I guess.
Rotate.
Make it like that.
Then we can move it the other way.
Amazing.
I'm gonna make room for this.
Let's put these on this side.
But why are they doing that?
Do I have to manually rotate that?
This is a little finicky.
Like, you would think a part that is made for storing stuff like this...
would be less finicky.
And then rotate.
There's probably keybinds for this.
I need to start learning that.
This is probably painful to look at.
There you go.
Actually, let me look at my cheat sheet.
What does it say?
Uh, VAB...
Toggle angle snap.
Move...
Zoom...
Oh!
One, two, three, four!
Hey!
Okay, sweet!
Now I just need to remember which one is switch.
Nice!
Oh, this is gonna be so much easier now.
Let's put that...
Like that!
I actually like it.
Maybe we rotate it.
So that's...
Uh, three.
Click on it.
Oh, no.
Not that way.
Can I undo?
Wait, undo?
Uh...
Undo, undo...
Undo...
No way.
Ahoy!
Huge.
Look at that.
Oh, no.
Why is the axis of rotation there?
That ruffles my feathers slightly.
I like it.
This is a little cramped in there, but you know.
The question is, though...
Wait, wait, wait.
I'm just confused here.
Like...
How is this gonna even work?
So...
How do I put this in there?
Because I can't, uh...
Leave the aircraft after it's...
I needed some kind of upgrade for that.
Hold on.
Save.
Which one did I need to upgrade for that?
Oh, look at this.
Tracking station upgrade required for flight planning?
Wait, what?
Flight planning?
I like that.
How does that work?
Kerbals can perform EVAs.
I can afford it.
But it's gonna mean we have 14,000 left.
This is, like, nothing.
Ooh, shit.
Oh, I don't know if I can do this.
Oy, oy, oy.
Wait, what about this one?
Oh, we can commit more?
Okay, I don't care about that.
Okay, I'm actually gonna do this.
We're gonna be low on money.
Okay.
So now we can do EVA, dude.
Can't wait to see that.
Can I cram Bob inside this service module?
I wanna bring him.
I wanna bring a scientist for this.
He needs to go in there.
It's gonna be fine.
Okay, so the reason I thought about this now is because...
How else am I gonna put stuff in there if I can't do EVA?
But now I can do EVA.
Extra vehicular activity, by the way.
That's what that means.
It means leaving the spacecraft in space...
And going for a spacewalk.
Sounds hella awesome.
This rocket has already proven itself.
This is like a winner.
This is now the science orbiter.
One.
Boom.
Okay.
And I guess this means...
Yo!
Check it out, check it out.
We're gonna do...
Because we're not gonna need this later, right?
Because we're gonna take the data from there.
And bring it into the storage unit.
So this is...
No, wait.
We do this.
There.
Here.
That's what we do.
So that means...
We do this.
These two.
Blow that off.
Start that.
Yep.
This looks good.
Bro, should I...
I'm thinking of bringing Bob.
Bob.
Bob, you're coming with me.
Bob, you are steering this vessel.
You are steering it.
We're gonna have to do...
We can make it happen.
Let me just confirm here.
Yep.
Okay, let me just...
Look through everything again.
Here.
Yes.
Save.
Let's do it.
Science Orbiter 1 with Bob Kerman.
It's about to have its maiden voyage.
Here we go.
I'm actually a little nervous.
Also, look at the launch pad, by the way.
It looks different too now.
I just noticed that.
After we upgraded it.
Here we go!
Wait, I'm still able to control, right?
I am.
Okay, good.
Uh-oh.
We're actually kind of falling out.
It's already a bad idea.
Oh, shit.
I can't...
Yeah, I can't do SES.
That's fine, though.
That's expected.
Bob, you...
You better...
You better do this.
You're a scientist.
You're smart.
You can figure it out.
Maybe with Valentina on the phone.
Okay, let's slightly go this way now.
But only very slightly.
It's 8,000.
Starting to rotate slightly.
Bob, you...
Hold on to that stick.
Oh, shit.
Uh-oh.
We're losing control.
Come on, Taurus!
Fuck!
Okay, hold it.
Hold it.
Oh, God.
The ball is rotating like crazy.
Keep it on the line.
Eye on the ball.
We don't care about rotation.
Fuck the rotation.
We're just gonna...
We're gonna adapt.
Overcome.
I Ching.
Darwin.
Come on.
Oh, my God.
It's getting harder to control.
Maybe we just need to ease off.
Okay.
Next!
How's it look?
Maybe?
Okay, I'm not sure.
We'll have to see.
We're gonna have to burn early.
Let's not forget.
Early burn.
That means now.
Burn along here.
And...
Go!
Oh!
Start the burn.
Come on.
Keep it aligned.
Right there.
Bob, you glorious bastard.
You're doing it.
Look at you.
All your hours in Microsoft Flight Simulator has paid off.
You nerd.
I'm not even looking at anything except keeping the ball in the correct spot here.
I don't know why it wants to change direction so much.
Shouldn't it just stay in one direction once it's there?
Oh wait, I guess we're still kind of in the atmosphere.
Uh-oh.
That's why.
There's air resistance.
That's what's happening.
That's why it's hard to control.
Actually, it's not that hard right now.
It's fine.
We're chilling.
Maximum chill.
So I think we were at like 2,200 or 2,300 meters per second last time, which means we should probably be in orbit very soon here.
Let's go to 2,300 just to be safe.
Whoa, what the fuck is going on with the camera?
Stop.
You are magnificent.
Incredible.
And now we do science.
Let's have a look, shall we?
Status, zero experiments.
Let's see the mystery goo.
There's probably nothing new there.
There's a little bit of new, but not enough new.
In fact, you know what?
We're not done burning.
I'm not fucking leaving!
Come on, Bob.
Keep an eye on it.
Good enough.
Stop there.
Okay, good.
Now.
Stop rotating.
There we go.
That's good enough.
Thermometer is nothing.
And there was also something else.
The other side.
There it is.
Pressure data.
It's nothing.
Okay.
But this one.
Conduct material study.
The microgravity has greatly affected the growth of crystalline structures.
Nice.
This is the 15 we didn't get last time.
And I guess we can...
So now we just gotta wait until we're on the other side.
In fact, I really want to get into the lid area.
There we go.
Oh, that's better.
Now we're gonna start to move away from Kerbin here.
God, this game is so much fun, dude.
Holy shit.
Oh, let's...
Crew report.
Crew report while in space high over Kerbin.
From up here, the desert and the oceans look like one giant beach.
Beaches are fun.
Bob, that's definitely a lie.
I know you've never been on a beach.
Come on.
You were playing Pong.
Wait, transfer data?
We
didn't even need to go EVA or whatever.
Wait, how?
How?
Ah, but wait, I can't reset.
Wait a second, though.
Temperature, nothing.
I think we already got this data, didn't we?
Pressure, nothing.
This one.
Wait, review data?
Transfer data?
Data transfer blocked by other dialog...
Oh.
Transfer data?
Oh my god.
It's so cool that I can do that.
And then?
Wait, why can't I...
I can't click on the goo anymore.
For some reason.
Okay, let's try...
Oh, we can go EVA, dude.
Here we go.
Dude, what about a safety tether here?
You crazy?
Uh...
I am scared.
Holy shit.
Oh god.
Can I...
Can I reach?
Come on.
Bob.
Do I let go?
Ha ha ha!
Hold on.
I need to...
Yeah.
Everything's fine.
This is fine.
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha.
Shit.
I...
Oh, I can't reach still.
Wait, up.
Oh no.
Wait, wait.
Uh...
Look at the key mines here.
Flights.
Uh...
Cut throttle.
Toggle SAS.
Toggle RCS.
Toggle RCS, maybe?
Ha!
Yes!
Oh my god, this is...
Okay, sideways.
How do I go up?
Down.
I and K?
Wait, that's not even working.
This cheat sheet fucking sucks.
Uh...
Wait.
Increase.
Oh!
Shift and control.
The cheat sheet says I and K on the keyboard.
Fucking liar.
Yes!
Restore!
Media restored.
Module is operational again.
Now we conduct study because we're further away from Kirban.
22.5!
This far out, the Badlands have little to no noticeable effect on your array of samples.
Wait, can I rotate?
Oh, I guess...
Yeah.
Whee!
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha!
This is fine.
Oh wait, let me...
Let me try this and then...
Whee!
Ha ha ha ha ha!
This is so good!
Look at this!
Bob is having the time of his life!
Oh, shit.
Let's...
Okay, calm down.
Calm down.
Okay.
Please don't get sick...
In your helmet.
If you do get sick, I'm gonna have to do this.
I don't wanna look at that.
In fact, we probably should have the visor down when looking at the sun, huh?
Oh, shit.
No.
Oh, fuck.
Wait, that way.
Oh, this is...
This is...
This is scary, dude!
Nailed it.
Okay, now...
No!
This way.
And now...
Slowly...
Let's just wait.
Wait, wait, wait.
Wait, take data?
Oh!
Collect data?
And now...
Store experiments.
Yes, dude!
They both go in there!
It works, dude!
I now have two science junior experiments in here.
Restore!
Observe.
Okay, we get a little bit of science.
It appears to vibrate merrily.
Alright.
We can store that too, maybe?
Oh, I have to collect it first.
Collect data.
Store experiments.
We have four in there now!
Log temperature.
Nothing new there.
Let's see if I can get to the other side real quick here.
I'm a pro now.
Oh, it's actually kind of nice that he sort of angles himself towards where I'm pointing the camera.
Oh.
Wait, can I actually go...
First person?
Oh, no, I can't!
Oh, my God, imagine.
Nothing.
Okay.
What if I keep...
Wait a minute.
Restore?
Because we're gonna splash down as well, right?
Hopefully.
And then we're gonna do it again.
Well, let me just do it one more time.
Let's see here.
So last time was high over Kerbin.
Okay, it's the same.
So we reset it.
Now we wait.
Let me see where we are.
Oh, this is so cool.
Bob Kerbin has a velocity of 1400 meters per second.
I like that it's saying Bob just has this velocity.
What about...
Can I see the vessel as well?
Behind him?
Maybe it's like the angle or...
I mean, we should have the exact same velocity, of course, because we're right next to each other.
Okay, now we go...
Nope.
Fuck.
Dude, imagine just floating away with the...
Wait, can I...
Do I actually have infinite...
Fuel?
I'm actually getting scared already.
Can I sort of see?
Oh, my God.
We don't even have...
Dude, imagine losing fuel and floating away.
Then it's time to start pooping.
I mean, uh, farting.
Crap.
That was actually so lucky that I just happened to be there.
All right, let's, let's, uh, let's board.
This was so good.
Now, but wait, wait, we're not done yet.
We still have to come home.
And we don't have SAS.
Bob, you have been miraculous so far.
But can you pull off the return?
That's what matters.
Ah, but wait a second.
We can't splash down and do this, because we're gonna...
We're gonna get rid of this module now.
Shit.
Ah, well.
I guess it is what it is.
Dang it.
Let's start burning, uh, retrograde here.
Turn the vessel.
There it is.
Keep it on...
On the...
All...
Let's see.
That's perfect.
That is perfect.
In fact, we could probably, uh...
Make it a little more shallow, because it does look a little aggressive, doesn't it?
Especially for...
Bob, who's a little, uh, noob.
When it comes to this, he's not a pilot.
Bring it back towards the vector.
I'm gonna come in at a little shallower angle here.
That's perfect.
Bob, you have done it.
Time to disengage.
Here we go.
Three.
Two.
One.
I
love separating stages.
Let's close these doors.
There we go.
And now we just wait.
I'm gonna gently fall back.
Boy!
Okay, we're not even that close.
Because it feels like we're way closer.
Uh, other way.
Now we really have to focus.
Keep it on retrograde.
Keep it aligned.
I mean, as long as this is...
This is going pretty okay.
And you know what?
Maybe the best thing I can do is actually not to touch the controls too much.
Because the forces should just align me correctly here.
If I get flipped, then it's game over, but...
The air itself should keep me aligned.
Oh, I need to...
We're not even close to the...
Atmosphere yet.
Calm down now.
Get aligned.
Keep it there.
Come on, Bob.
Dude, we're at...
2,500 meters.
This is the fastest we've ever approached...
The planet.
Not only is Bob being tested...
He's being tested way more than the others.
And he was never trained for this.
2,600 right now.
Holy fuck.
Keep it aligned.
Here we go.
It's starting.
Keep it aligned.
The air is not helping me stabilize it.
I really thought it would...
Do that.
Oh, no.
Keep it in.
Shit.
Oh, no.
Oh, God.
It's so sensitive.
Come on.
We gotta survive the blackout stage.
Dude, I'm actually exhausted.
My head.
It really wants to...
Turn.
It really wants to turn over.
Fuck.
It's not aligning automatically at all.
We're slowing down.
I can't look at the...
I can't look at the numbers.
I have to focus.
Oh, my God.
My hand actually hurts.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah.
Oh, we did it.
Holy dude, my head actually hurts.
Like my fingers, because I was like pressing so hard.
Oh, man.
That was amazing.
Bob, you are incredible.
I think you're the MVP now.
At first, it was Jeb, then it was Valentina, but now you have taken the throne.
You are the one.
You are actually the guy.
You are him.
Let's see what we got in terms of crew report here.
Uh, what do we currently have?
Okay, we have a good one.
Let's keep that.
Let's not ruin the day.
Parachute.
Through the clouds.
Oh, please let us not be electrocuted now.
On the way down.
It will be...
Frickin' scary.
Oh, this is a weird effect.
We're apparently moving faster than the water droplets.
That makes no sense.
Okay, now it looks better.
Man, this is beautiful.
What a trip, huh?
So cozy.
Oi!
Don't be scared, Bob.
Don't be scared.
That's nothing compared to what you just went through.
Can I see like a...
Do we have an altimeter?
I guess the atmosphere indicator here.
But maybe...
Oh!
There we go!
Altitude.
We're almost there.
And...
Desert!
Wait, it's raining in the desert?
Sick.
Let's go on a spacewalk.
I was about to say.
Take data?
What about EVA report?
Wait!
EVA report?
I should have done an EVA report when I did an EVA.
In other words, I should have done a report while I did an EVA.
Time to stretch your legs.
I mean, all right.
Okay.
That was a freaking successful mission.
Holy shit.
That was beautiful.
46 signs.
Dude, we have 84 signs right now.
And Bob leveled up.
I want to see what he can do now.
Also, warp to sunrise.
That's it.
Toast with cheese and black coffee for everyone.
You deserve it.
Let's have a look here.
Oh, I can't afford this stage yet, but it would be cool.
I really need to think about this one.
Oh, look at all this.
Oh, this is 90!
No!
We're so close.
But maybe it's worth getting this.
Or maybe it's not.
Let me see what I can get here.
Oh.
Lots of cool-looking engines.
And look at this one.
That's a long boy.
Oh my god, I love all of these.
Oh my god, there's so much.
Fuel systems.
What is this stuff?
Space exploration?
Cargo storage unit.
EVA repair kit?
Conformal storage unit.
Hitchhiker storage container.
Mobility enhancer.
You mean a ladder?
Work lamp.
Yo, rover...
Rover, uh...
Wheels.
Probodobine experiment control station.
Dude, this game is amazing.
Goob ED monitor?
What even...
What...
EVA experiments kit?
Ah!
What do you mean?
Oh my god, I want all of this.
Wait, how far am I in this tech tree?
Holy shit!
Dude, I don't even want to look at what's back there.
Wait, I want to see how much it costs.
Thousand?
What the...
How?
How are you going to get thousand?
That's crazy.
Holy shit.
Oh, man.
I...
I want this.
I want to go bigger.
I want to go pro.
Put me in the game, coach.
I'm ready.
Wow.
Uh...
Dude, you know what we need to do?
This is it.
Check it out.
We're going to make a tiny little vessel now.
Get rid of this crap.
No, keep this crap, actually.
Get rid of that crap.
And...
And that, too.
And then we're going to do...
We're going to do...
A swivel, baby.
We're going to swivel it.
And then we're going to...
Uh...
We don't need this anymore.
Put that on.
And then we do this and that.
We don't need this anymore.
Get rid of that.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
And then I guess we don't even need this anymore.
Get rid of that.
I think.
No, wait, actually, I regret.
Put it back.
Okay, this is it.
Wait, there's way too much fuel here.
Give me this one.
But if... Okay, in that case, let's just... We're gonna flee it.
Flee.
We're even gonna say... Half fuel.
Half fuel on that.
We're gonna turn it yellow.
Yellow booster.
And then?
We're gonna call it...
Mini... Mini science.
No.
Miniature...
Uh... Water science.
We go to the beach.
Everyone deserves it after that.
Who's piloting?
Bob?
Yes.
Bob is the man.
I love scientists way more than the pilots now.
They're my favorite ever.
They're so good.
Now, let's see here.
Conduct material study.
And we already did this one.
Actually, still give some.
And I guess I can just take it.
Because we can reset.
EVA?
Ah, but wait, can I reach?
I can.
How come I couldn't reach in space?
Maybe it's different when it's spacewalk.
Collect data.
Uh...
Restore.
Open.
We're gonna put that in there.
Let me just see these as well.
Just to double check here.
There's a little bit in there.
We'll take that.
Restore.
Store.
What about these?
These are done.
I think we've...
Properly exhausted these experiments.
Yep.
Okay.
Now we close.
And we enter.
Now we launch and go to the water.
Oh shit, this is...
This is a hard one to control.
Oh shit!
That's it!
I guess we're not going to the water anytime soon.
Never mind.
We're going somewhere else.
That's fine though.
That's okay.
Wait.
Turn it around.
There we go.
That's more like it.
Never mind.
It really wants to become a missile.
Bob!
Let's conduct material study now.
Nice!
The less resilient samples appear to have splattered around the interior.
Forming new and interesting color combinations.
Transfer data.
Oh wait.
Open this.
Maybe we can even see if there's anything...
Interesting here.
Nothing there.
What about this one?
Nothing.
Why is this so fascinating to do?
Like I'm like obsessed with this.
Keep that experiment.
Transfer that to this one.
Transfer this one to that one.
Close these doors.
Maybe close these doors too.
Like that.
And now we land.
There we go.
And then we're going to have Bob reset it.
And we're going to perform an amazing experiment.
We're going to have Bob go home empty handed.
Because apparently something just exploded.
Why?
What happened?
The shores appear to have a blue liquid nearby.
Okay.
That's cool.
But isn't that just water?
Seems we are on a home planet.
That's correct Bob.
Spoken like a true scientist.
Okay.
So we need to figure out why that just exploded.
Were we coming in too hot?
That what happened?
But hey.
Look.
90 science.
It's exactly what we needed.
So Bob.
You did it.
It's perfect.
90.1 in fact.
That's wonderful.
All right.
Let me see here.
Science.
Tolerance.
6 meters per second impact.
Oh.
I didn't even notice how fast we were going.
But we must have gone faster.
Maybe we need two parachutes.
Yeah.
Okay.
I guess that's the change I would make there.
Let me actually see here.
Here.
We would want these I guess.
Whoa.
They're huge.
Make two of them.
You know what we could do?
Check it out.
We can save a bit of money.
And just put one of them.
On here.
Then we come down at an angle.
And because we come down at an angle.
We're also going to have more surface area exposed.
So we're going to be even slower.
And we save money.
And not only that.
Since we have a bit of extra weight here.
It's automatically going to turn towards the ocean.
Oh my god.
It's perfect.
Let's quickly do it.
It's like a genius.
I'm a genius.
Here we go.
Ah.
I need to do this again.
We got a little bit of science there.
So we transfer.
So here.
Wait.
Transfer.
How come I can't do this anymore?
Oh, did I already do it?
Oh, I did it without even thinking.
Well, I'm so fast.
Holy shit.
Dang.
EVA.
Restore.
Back in.
Close these up.
Ready for launch.
And.
Oh shit.
Oh, it really wants to turn right.
I underestimated.
How much that parachute was going to affect it.
See ya.
Let's wait until we're a little over the ocean here.
Because we're going to the beach.
Right here.
Beach party.
We.
Ah.
We missed the beach.
But it's okay.
I mean, we're going skinny dipping.
Yes.
Look.
It's exactly the way I imagined it.
Okay, 4.8 meters per second.
That's definitely less than six.
And maybe because we're hitting water, it's going to be even less impactful.
Conduct material study right now.
Oh, that gives me almost nothing.
But I'll take it.
And we can even open this.
We can transfer it again to that one.
I wonder if it's like a proximity thing.
If I had put this way further away, if I still could have transferred.
I guess I'll find out later.
Close the doors before we hit the water.
Hey, look.
It's Subnautica below here.
This reminds me of Subnautica a little bit.
Oh, it's safely on the ocean.
It's beautiful.
Now, let's rotate this slightly.
Like that.
Because that's the hatch.
Now, we're going to have to do EVA.
Restore.
Conduct study.
There we go.
1.3 science.
We take that.
And I think I'm good, man.
Unless we quickly open this.
We already did this, actually.
That's it.
Collected.
Tag it and bag it.
We got two science out of that.
That was maybe a little too overkill for two science.
But, you know.
Hey, now it's done.
Guys.
Are you ready?
Oh, wait.
This is expensive?
Wait, I have no money.
Oh, fuck.
Wait, wait, wait.
Do I sell my shit to get money?
You can get money.
Which one gives money?
Bailout grant?
Get funds.
Lose reputation?
How do I even see my reputation?
Is it that one?
We got money.
Science.
This has to be reputation.
I can't see a numerical value, though.
So, I don't know how much I actually have.
Maybe I click on something?
Oh, yeah.
There's a star right there.
I just saw it.
Fundraising campaign.
Takes reputation gains.
But isn't this from now on and going forward?
Wait a minute.
I could also just do a mission.
Why didn't I think of this?
Conduct temperature surveys of Kerbin.
Measure the temperature in flight.
Oh, that's...
That's a lot of spots.
But there's a lot of money involved.
Test kickback solid fuel booster in flight over Kerbin.
Okay.
These are both escape trajectories.
That's not easy to attain.
This one seems easy.
Back thumper solid fuel booster at the launch site.
That's like almost no money at all.
Let me look at this again.
I think I may have fucked myself a little bit by upgrading that one facility.
Spending all my money on it.
Let's try this.
So, we get some funds, but we lose reputation.
Effective immediately.
The thing is, I don't know how much reputation I...
Oh.
Let's just...
Do this one?
Are you sure you want to activate this strategy?
It will apply immediately and reset.
Yes.
Oh, yeah.
It went from green to yellow.
Oh, that's zero right there.
That's 25.
That's minus 25.
The numbers are so tiny.
Okay, we got some money now.
20,000.
Holy shit.
We are in monetary trouble here.
The thing is, do I even need to buy this?
What is the next plan?
I guess the next plan is to go to the moon.
Maybe this is what we need for that.
Let me see this.
Skipper.
Oh, it's very powerful.
Holy shit.
568 kilonewtons.
This one is not powerful, but it has insane ISP.
Meaning efficiency.
So this is like that other one, but different.
It has four, it seems.
I guess it must be better.
A more reasonable engine for rough economic times.
The poodle engine doubles as a barbecue when at low power.
Sweet.
We can roast some sausages.
This super heavy booster is designed to be recovered after jettisoning.
Once recovered, it is refurbished and refueled for another launch.
What?
Interesting.
How?
Are you going to recover that?
It's a solid fuel booster.
Once you start that, there's no going back.
How are you going to control that descent?
Okay.
Hmm.
I think I want to buy...
Wait, so let me see this one.
This one has...
374...
This one is obviously meant to get off Kerbin.
This is the engine to get for this.
You know?
I think I need this.
It costs 14,000...
I don't have money for that.
We're going to have to try something else.
Maybe we can go to the moon with what we have here.
We need to try something.
We need to, you know...
Back to the drawing board here.
Let's start with...
The science orbiter.
And...
Actually, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Let's say I don't buy that...
Research there.
And I...
Choose something else.
Look at these...
Engines here.
They're like tiny.
16 kilonewtons?
Are you kidding me?
What's that even for?
Maybe, like, little satellites or something.
Probes.
Wait, general construction?
No.
Flight control...
Space exploration.
Oh, man.
I...
I don't know what to pick.
Oh, my God.
I'm so...
I'm overwhelmed.
I need science.
What science?
Which one has science?
Actually, I need money, but...
Of course, we need science as well.
This one, maybe.
EVA experiments kit.
Performing experiments in EVA?
Or during EVA?
Man, the...
The decisions you have to make here are not easy.
This is...
This is tough.
I think I'm gonna save my science.
We're gonna start earning some money.
I'm gonna try and see if I can get to the moon here.
The thing is, though, we're gonna have one shot at this.
20,000 in the bank.
This rocket right here costs 12,000.
We have one shot at the moon.
Uh...
Oh, God.
I mean, all we have to do is a flyby, right?
Isn't that what it said?
Yeah, okay.
Gather scientific data from the moon.
But does that mean I can...
You know, do a crew report while flying by?
Does that count?
I guess it must.
Otherwise, why would it say flyby, right?
Uh...
Dude, we also need to figure out how fast the moon is moving.
Compared to where we are.
How the hell are we gonna figure that out?
I don't know, actually.
Huh.
Maybe it's not time for the moon yet.
I feel like to perform a mission like that, we're gonna need a couple of tries, you know?
Like, even NASA didn't go to the moon in one go.
They had a bunch of Apollo missions before the actual Apollo mission.
So that's what we're gonna do here as well, you know?
Um...
So I think first off, it's just...
Maybe we do some contracts, right?
That's like the idea here.
That's how we get some money.
Let's do some contracts!
That sounds good.
For example, this one.
It's trivial, apparently.
And it does pay okay.
It's not that bad.
Ferry a VIP.
It's not even that much money, but we get...
Uh...
Reputation from it.
I wonder what reputation it's good for.
Maybe it's, uh...
The more reputation you have, the better the contracts pay.
You know, because you're, like, famous.
And you know how to get shit done.
I'm gonna...
I'm gonna try these.
I'm gonna take one of these.
That one.
Now, let's see where that is.
Wait, why are there so many?
Take pressure readings in flight below 19,000.
Near Yuman's Lament.
Okay, that is that one.
Oh, that's really close.
That's actually kinda neat.
Isn't that, like, super easy?
It's, like, mega easy.
Easy money.
Let's do a little, uh...
Plane here.
So, we definitely need a pilot for this one.
Let's see here.
Maybe we start with the miniature water science.
And we get rid of all the science.
Ha ha ha ha.
Actually, we just start with this.
It's that simple.
And then we, uh...
Ideally want something...
We can control a little bit.
So, I'm thinking...
A swivel, of course.
Dude, the reliance sucks.
The swivel is where it's at.
That looks cool.
Maybe more aerodynamic, too.
I don't know.
Um...
That...
Perhaps we add some...
Just a couple of these.
Three of them.
A tiny rocket ship.
Look at that.
That's pretty.
And, of course...
Yeah, Jebediah is fine.
Let's see if we can do this.
So, we need to be...
Below 20,000...
Near Yuman's Lament.
Wait, is that...
Are we not there now?
Oh, wait.
Take pressure readings.
Hold on.
If I'm on the pad, can I...
Oh, I guess I can recover a vessel.
Hey.
Well, there you go.
I was like, do I have to launch?
But I guess I don't.
We need a pressure reading.
So, that would be...
Science.
Barometer.
Boom.
That's it.
Maybe even, like, here.
Beautiful.
Okay.
So, now we have to see here.
Activate navigation.
Speed.
Actually, maybe we...
We don't go too fast at once.
SAS.
Oh, look.
We leveled up.
I can't click on it, though.
Now I can.
Let's calm down a bit.
We don't want to go too high.
Also, um...
Oh, it's a little the other way.
Oh.
Just point towards it, I guess.
Why is it blinking?
What does that mean?
We're approaching.
And we are way below 20,000.
We should be here.
Maybe we need to be really close.
Try now.
Oh, there we go.
Okay.
So, I just had to do that.
I see.
For some reason, I was waiting for this to become green.
And then I had to click on it or something.
But I was like...
Oh, yeah.
We gotta take the pressure reading.
Okay.
And now...
We just do a simple parachute like that.
Sometimes you gotta do the...
The shitty job, you know?
To get the money rolling in.
Whoa!
Are you okay, Jebediah?
That was quite a...
Um...
Violence.
Did that just break?
I think we just broke the rocket part.
Look, it's gone.
Oh, okay.
Not that we need it.
The only thing that's important is...
This thing, right?
Crew report?
Hey, there's signs there!
No, not the water!
I know.
You wanna get away from the planet.
I get it.
Even got some signs out of that.
And look at that!
30,000 now.
Let's see what else we got.
We can do a couple of these.
I mean, earning some money here?
In fact, can we do multiple at once?
Oh, wait.
I can only have two contracts at a time.
Right.
Okay.
That's fine.
But now we already have the vessel ready.
Is it also like a...
Pressure reading?
It is.
Above 17,000.
Okay, so this one is a little different.
Not sure if we have enough juice for this one, though.
Can we get that high enough on this tank?
Let's see.
Wait.
Is it that one?
Near sector Q8WJ.
Oh, it is that one.
Agency Clampotron.
We gotta target that.
I guess it's like that way-ish.
We don't have enough juice for this, I think.
But let's just see.
Maybe I'm wrong.
Like over...
Oh, I went the wrong way!
Shit!
Ah, it's already fucked.
I went the wrong way again.
Ah, no.
Ah, crap.
Stop it.
Stop it, stop it, stop it, stop it.
Terrible.
I couldn't see the thing on the...
Nath bowl, man.
Where am I supposed to go?
I think it's on the other side of the bowl, which is confusing.
Dang.
Well, that wasn't successful.
Dude, money is suddenly a big problem.
Huh?
Chibidiah!
After everything!
It said the chute got destroyed by heat!
What the hell?
What do you mean?
Not like this?
No.
Catastrophic failure!
Oh my god.
That's so sad.
Why did it have to end like this?
Jebediah is gone.
Trying to do a shitty contract for Clampatron.
Clampatron is now the biggest enemy of the space agency.
Fuck those people.
I will never do a contract for them again.
I got fucked by that.
Except I still have the contract.
We gotta do it.
What happens if we don't do it?
We're gonna lose money.
That's bad.
That's actually really bad.
I feel like we should do this now.
I keep saying that.
But now we have 30,000, right?
So, maybe that's enough.
To get the ball rolling here.
We could buy something here, perhaps.
That will put us on the path to the moon.
I'll take the skipper liquid fuel engine here.
Oh, I have to...
Boy,
oh boy, oh boy.
Wait, do I want this?
Is this even gonna help me?
You know what?
I think it's time we look at...
No, give me this one.
How do I...
Oh.
I'm so poor.
Oh my god.
It's so expensive.
Let me see the manual here.
Let me figure this out.
Is there like a...
Idiot's Guide to go to the moon?
I mean, isn't it just a glorified home and transfer?
And then you have to predict where the moon is gonna be?
That's pretty much it, right?
But let me see here.
Like, I think I know how to do it, but...
Isn't there like...
Celestial bodies?
I guess it would be Kerbin.
And then maybe it showed...
Oh, here.
There are two moons circling Kerbin.
The moon, which is a nearby trip for the Adventurous.
And Minmus.
Seems minty fresh somehow.
Yeah, it's kind of minty colored.
Easter eggs.
Other places of interest.
Throughout the solar system, there are many places to see and visit.
This includes a number of unusual objects and places of interest.
I wonder how many you can find.
Dude!
Let's try and find as many as we can!
I mean, this is like a long-term thing, but...
I want to find them!
Hell yeah!
Orbital Basics, maybe?
It's not saying anything about...
Specific sort of...
Translunar injection burns.
That's what I need to know, right?
Communications network.
Career.
Maybe something about money.
Contracts.
It will sometimes be offered contracts related to vessels or Kerbos you have out there too.
So keep an eye out for opportunities.
What?
Okay.
Science.
Science!
Wait!
Asteroid mining?
Scanning?
Oh my god!
Okay, dude.
I'm losing my mind over this.
This is crazy.
Controls.
What the?
Maneuver tool.
What?
Alarm clock.
Oh yeah, I guess I have that.
Right here.
What's the point of it?
Planetary transfer window.
Oh.
Right.
I guess you wanna...
If you wanna go to another planet, you gotta wait for the planets to be in the specific spots you want them to be.
To make it as easy as possible.
So this can calculate that.
What am I looking for here?
Oh!
Look at us!
There's keybinds here too.
So I'll go ship labels?
Hmm, okay.
Dude, I think...
I know how to get to the moon.
We just gotta...
guesstimate where it's gonna be.
Pretty much.
Um...
This is not gonna get us to the moon.
We need another one.
Wait, now we unlocked a new thing, didn't we?
Let me take this one.
Close that one.
That one.
Oh my god, it's big.
Dude.
This is gonna be insane.
It's gonna be so easy?
Am I crazy?
Oh, wait a minute.
This doesn't even...
Do we have a tank that fits that?
Wait, this one is actually a little bigger.
Oh!
No.
What the f...
Wait, this is way too big for me!
That's what she said.
No, but really, I...
It's big.
It's too big.
I need, uh...
I need fuel tanks.
Shit.
Well, okay, that's not happening then.
Okay, if we're going to the moon...
Let's get rid of all the extra weight we don't need.
So I'm serious.
We're gonna get rid of all this crap.
Nobody needs that.
We're gonna go in like that.
Like this.
Like that.
And let's do...
Let's do...
One more tank here.
Like that.
Make these orange.
Because it looks cool.
Kind of fits this one too, actually.
And then we're gonna...
Dude!
Five thousand!
Wait, really?
How did I just gain that much?
Was it just that one tank?
Wait.
Oh!
Five thousand two hundred!
We have a lot of Delta V here.
But...
We also don't have a lot of thrust to weight ratio on the first stage.
Ah, maybe this is a bit too much.
Let me actually cut it down just a bit there.
So this one...
We cut there and we do that.
Oh my god.
Uh...
Moon...
Explorer...
One.
We...
Meet the moon.
And high five.
Hit.
And that's about it.
We're not gonna do more than that.
Save.
Okay.
We have reduced the weight as much as possible now.
No more science.
No more bullshit.
Keeping it minimal.
Go.
First things first.
We get to orbit.
And then we take it from there.
If it doesn't look good.
Or it smells bad.
Or something else.
Then we abandon the mission and come home.
I lost Jebediah.
I can't lose Valentina.
Lift off.
We're going to the moon.
We're actually...
We're not getting that high.
But maybe it's okay.
Wait, I forgot we have the second stage.
Haha.
We have three stages here.
This is just to get through the thickest part of the atmosphere.
Boom.
This mission has to succeed.
We are poor as fuck.
A lot of things can go wrong.
Let's start turning slightly.
We're going to try and make this as efficient as we possibly can.
Slowly turn.
Let me just keep it like this for a bit.
Wait for the vector to approach me here.
Actually, a little more.
There.
Let's keep it like that.
We're going to run out of fuel here, but that's okay.
That's by design.
Let's have a look.
How far up are we?
It's cutting it close.
I would have preferred to go a little higher there.
But it shall do.
It will do.
We're going quite slow.
I think now is a good time.
Point directly that way.
Burn has begun.
We have to keep an eye on the fuel.
We cannot be running out of fuel.
And be stuck up here.
I feel like I ideally shouldn't be doing this part of the...
mission.
While still in the atmosphere.
Like, we should definitely have been higher at this point, you know?
We are bleeding off a lot of energy through air right now.
Honestly, it's looking...
I probably could have started that burn a little earlier, even.
But it's not that bad looking.
We still have a lot of fuel left.
We started way too late.
I keep underestimating how long it's going to take.
This engine is so weak.
We should be speeding up faster and faster, though.
Because we keep losing mass, right?
Okay.
Yeah.
We're going faster and faster.
Slowly appearing.
There it is.
Maybe stop, like, there.
Oh my god, the moon is right there, dude!
Can I not somehow do anything?
Wait.
Oh, it's moving this way.
You can see it in the line.
Okay, good.
So it's moving...
It's going to be a fucking shot in the dark, man.
Initial instinct, maybe, like, 45 degrees that way, like here.
Dude, what if we...
Like, if we end up with no fuel, we're fucked.
This is maybe too risky.
I don't think I can do this.
Okay, let's just try it.
This mission has to work.
How far are we actually above the surface?
Oh my god!
Okay, we're not bleeding off speed that much.
Okay, it's not that bad.
I thought we were, like...
I mean, it is kind of bad, but, you know.
We definitely don't want to burn exactly opposite the moon, because the moon's going to be moving.
So I'm going to say, like, here.
Let's try and aim for that.
Which means we need to be, like, here.
Which I could speed up more.
Because we're that low.
I mean, okay, we're getting a little higher.
Valentina is excited.
Okay, I think about...
Now.
Maybe a little more.
Maybe,
like...
Let's dig right there.
That's directly opposite.
Okay, so slow down.
Now we want to point a longer vector.
Here we go.
This is a complete shot in the dark, by the way.
The good news is...
We're going to keep an eye on the fuel.
If we can't make it, or if we miss, or whatever...
Then we can always burn opposite and, you know, come back.
But we really have to...
We really have to be careful on the fuel there.
I don't think it's enough.
Oh, no.
Valentina might be dead, actually.
I'm just going to go for it.
Fuck it.
A little more.
Oh, my God.
It's going fast.
Boom.
Hopefully, we hit the sphere of influence.
And it's going to count as a flyby.
I mean, in any case, we're going to come home on this trajectory.
So, we're actually kind of safe.
Because we still have some fuel, and we can burn over here, and it should be okay.
Also, alignment here looks pretty good.
Let's see.
Oh, my God.
Let me see here.
Fly by the moon.
Gather scientific...
I guess we can do a crew report.
If that counts.
Return to Kerbin from a flyby.
Oh, my God.
Hoi, hoi, hoi.
Valentina.
Your fate is already sealed right now.
You will be going close to the moon.
Are you excited?
Yes.
Good.
You need that excitement.
Bank that energy.
Here we go.
You ready?
We're going to start time warping.
Settle down for the long nap.
Don't go gentle into that good night.
The moon is right there, look!
It's in the mirror.
I mean, window, not mirror.
Bye-bye, Kerbin.
Everyone say bye-bye, Kerbin.
Oh, man.
Dude, I feel like watching Interstellar after this.
Holy shit.
Damn.
It's going to become smaller and smaller.
Speed it up even more.
The moon is getting larger.
Look at that.
Let's try and angle it so that we have it in view here.
There it is.
Oh, look at that, dude!
Look at the planets on the right, too!
This almost looks like a logo.
Like, if you consider the whole frame.
It's so cool, man.
Let me angle that perfectly like that.
I'm looking at the OBS preview, and the chat is kind of ruining it.
You know, the little chat on top of the...
I'm sorry about the VOD people seeing the chat on top of it, because it's kind of amazing looking without the chat on top of the amazing screenshot here, you know?
Okay, so watch this.
We're going to speed up now.
I hope it's speeding up.
Oh, it is.
It is.
We're speeding up faster.
It's becoming bigger.
Dude, I have goosebumps.
What was that?
Oh, look at the...
You can see it speed up when I speed up, because the timer, see?
Whoa!
That's so dope.
That's a cool way to see whether or not you're in time warp.
Oh, it's the sun that appeared on the other side of that planet.
That's why it got so bright all of a sudden.
Damn.
Oh, man.
It's getting bigger.
It looks like we're really close, but if I open the map, we're probably, like, not even halfway.
Let's go even faster.
Can we go faster?
Oh, shit.
You can go really fast.
Let me just angle this.
Like that.
Dude, look at Kerbin.
It's so small.
Wow.
You know what we should do?
Should we go spacewalk?
Oh, my God.
Look, it's right there.
What about crew report?
Space high over Kerbin.
Okay.
I thought for sure we would have some kind of different situation here.
But okay.
Unless we've got to wait a little longer.
Let's keep fast-forwarding time.
Wait.
Are we going to miss it?
Hold on.
I'm actually going to look at the map.
Dude, we may actually hit it.
Depending on how fast that moves.
I forgot where it was when we started.
Wasn't it, like, over here?
Maybe we're going to miss it, actually.
Ah, the thing is, though, we're going to start moving slower and slower and slower as we come over here.
Right now we're moving at 800.
We're probably going to be at, like, 200 at the time we're over here.
If not even lower.
We may not be able to catch up to this bastard.
But who knows?
It depends on what this contract means, you know?
Like, how much grace do they give us in terms of proximity to count as a flyby, right?
This almost feels like a little flyby.
But I guess it means be in the sphere of influence.
We'll have to see.
Speed up.
We can do 50x right now.
100x.
You can actually see it moving.
I think it...
This is...
This looks like we're going to hit it.
I mean, we're going to be there, but I think we're going to end up being so slow that it's going to run away from us.
That's my prediction.
I think we're...
We're going to be too slow.
God, the game looks so much better without the UI.
It's actually crazy.
The UI looks kind of bad.
I got a...
Like, the UI in this game does not look good.
Compared to what the game has on offer here, like...
The UI is dragging the game down.
I mean, it is functional.
It's good in that sense.
But visually, not a big fan of the UI.
You know?
Okay, guys.
I'm actually going to make a prediction.
In the Twitch here.
I'm actually so excited.
Unless people have already done something.
I was going to make a...
Oh, wait.
Have you made a prediction already?
Okay, there is a prediction going.
I'm not going to do anything then.
I was going to say...
Are we going to make it to the moon, you know?
But, okay.
Let's see what happens.
It's like the perfect gambling setup.
Here we go, faster.
The clock is spinning.
Are we going to be there in time?
Whoa.
I feel like we're missing it.
Look.
It's moving out of...
I think it's getting bigger in size.
Slightly.
God, it looks so good.
Look at that.
The Terminator across it.
Even from here.
Speed up.
We're going to miss it.
It's totally pulling ahead.
Fuck.
Usually Jebediah is the one who's too short, you know?
Damn.
Oh, shit.
What's happening?
Do we have problems?
Oh.
Okay.
So, I thought that was a prediction.
I'm going to make a prediction.
Will we make it?
Answer?
Yes.
Oh, no.
It's going to be more like...
Hell, yeah.
No way.
Two minutes.
No.
One minute.
Yes.
There you go.
Enjoy.
Meanwhile, I'm going to slowly approach the moon here.
It's happening.
Dude, I'm...
I'm having such a fucking blast with this game so far.
This is insane.
We're speeding up slightly.
A little more.
I feel like the size of the moon is not increasing, guys.
And you know what that means.
Oh, my God.
Look.
Man, we should have gone a little further ahead.
Actually, what I should have done...
I should have burnt...
So that the apoapsis was a little further out as well.
Okay.
Let's speed up a little bit from here.
Yeah.
Look how slow we're moving.
Meanwhile, the moon...
Oh, shit.
Jackie's jumping on the table.
Hey, Jackie.
Come here.
Look at that.
I'm trying to go to the moon.
Oh, that's...
Okay, that was it.
She didn't want to be there anymore.
Hey, you know what?
My orbit line is going through the moon right now.
That's a success, in a way.
But look.
We're moving at 400 meters per second.
The moon is moving at 540.
Quick maths means we're not going to catch it, bro.
Unless we're already...
No, there's no way moon is having a bigger influence on our craft than the earth, right?
Let me see what the thing says.
It does not say anything green yet, so I think...
We may just be a little cooked here.
But let's see.
Let's speed up a bit more.
Whoa.
Oh, no.
Come back.
No.
It's moving away.
Shit, man.
God damn it.
Okay, well, let's see if we can do a crew report.
It's just the same.
There's just, like, no change.
Come on.
You see the moon up so close.
There's got to be something.
We can take photographs.
Don't we have a Nike...
Nike?
I mean, Nikon.
I mean, the shoe is not going to help us here.
If we had a bed, maybe we could zoom on it, but...
That's not happening right now.
All right.
Bye-bye, moon.
Bye-bye.
Okay, we got to go a little further ahead, then.
We're at APWAPs now-ish.
Hey, look at my prediction.
I said about 200 meters per second.
I was close.
All we need to do is, like, breathe...
Backwards.
And we will actually...
End up on...
Curbin again.
That's all we need to do right now.
Turn around.
Okay.
God, this game is amazing.
Dude, we're gonna...
We're gonna land at the space station.
At the space, uh...
Agency.
Watch.
Can't see shit from this angle.
Oh, fuck!
That's too much.
Oh, wait a sec.
Oh, that's crazy.
Oh, that's sick.
Oh, my God.
That's awesome.
Increase it a bit more now.
I'm looking over here.
That may be a little too much.
I'm not sure.
Let's click on this.
Dude, that's amazing.
There
we go.
We're not gonna end up at the space station.
Or, I mean, space center.
Unfortunately.
But, hey, you know what?
This was not a failure.
Because we got some kick-ass views of the moon, didn't we?
And now...
The Earth.
Or, I guess, Kerbin.
Look at that, man.
Wow, we can zoom a lot!
What the fuck?
Look at that!
Dude, look at the effect of the stars when you zoom.
This looks amazing.
Oh.
Wow.
Okay, it's time...
...to speed up.
Look at how slow we're moving.
What is the mission timer, anyway?
Oh, one day and one hour!
Interesting.
Whoa, the camera is messing with me right now.
Why is it not responding?
It's like a weird angle.
Oh!
What?!
Jesus Christ!
Okay!
Time warp...
Time warp's got hands!
Are you kidding me?!
Jesus fucking fuck!
That scared the crap!
I thought we were gonna crash!
Oh!
Okay, you wanna be careful with the time warp!
Shit!
I didn't know you were so unchilled like that!
Dang!
3,000 meters per second, by the way.
Wait, are we actually...
We have a heat shield.
Wait, are we okay?
I'm actually scared.
Valentina?
Are we good?
Okay, she looks...
She looks good.
She looks ready.
I mean, I can't really do much now.
Jesus, take the wheel.
Take the wheel.
Oh, man.
Oh, shit!
Oh!
Hello!
What's going on there, brother?
How's it hanging?
Just minding my own business here.
Yep, yep, yep, yep, yep, yep, yep, yep.
Ha ha ha!
I mean, it's holding steady, it seems.
We're bleeding off speed very slow, though.
If we hit denser atmosphere, this could be bad.
Can I, like, click on it?
Oh!
Look!
A blader!
It's, it's, uh...
Going down.
I think we're, I think we're fine.
We're totally cool.
We're chilling.
We go for the cinematic views.
Hoi, hoi, hoi!
Easy.
Valentina, it was a good effort.
Now we face another problem.
A problem more pressing than anything else.
Money.
That's right.
We may have run out of money.
This was the mission.
I'm actually not sure exactly how much we spent on this one.
But, uh...
We'll have to see.
Maybe we have enough money to do one last.
Now I know I need to aim a little further ahead.
Shoots her up.
Looking good.
There goes my other stage.
Rip.
God, I just love...
Like, the views.
It's just...
Half the amazingness of this game is just the views you're getting.
The sense of scale and...
Uh...
You know...
Distance and all that.
It's incredible.
It really is.
Now imagine...
This is just a game, right?
And it's not even that graphically amazing, if you think about it.
Imagine being up there for real.
In space.
Looking at the Earth.
Holy shit, man.
I would love to do that.
I would love that.
And there we are.
We made it.
Valentina.
Go do your best impression of...
Whatever her name is in...
Gravity.
It was her name.
The one from...
Miss Congeniality.
The one from A Perfect Murder.
I forgot her name.
Anyway...
We have made it home.
Nothing new there?
That's unfortunate.
The way she walks.
Up, da-da-da-da.
Like she didn't just go on the most amazing journey of...
Kerbal kind.
Alright.
Take me home.
Good effort.
Let's see how much money we have left.
12,000?
Ah!
We're not...
We're not gonna have enough for another one of those missions.
Okay.
Dude, my Tommy just rumbled like crazy.
I'm hungry.
I'm gonna have to scrounge together some money.
The way we're gonna save this space program...
Is we're gonna have to do a couple shitty missions at the Mission Control.
Can we even do it?
We cannot even do it because we don't have contracts.
But...
We can maybe do something here.
A bailout grant.
Oh wait, we did that already.
What about Research Right Sellout?
Wait!
20,000 for...
Half a science?
You're shitting me!
What?
Oh, wait, wait.
Oh.
It was...
32...
Money.
Not 32,000.
The fucking decimal...
Got me.
Shit.
Oh man, I thought we were...
I thought we were saved.
That's nuts.
Okay, let's see what else we got here.
I mean, I can probably...
Let's try and do this one.
We're gonna do this mission for these assholes.
We're gonna do it.
Clamp a Tron.
I will clamp your Tron.
This thing costs...
Oh wait, wait!
This thing costs 6,000!
It's super cheap!
How is this only 6,000?
This is like...
A generational ship.
Insanity.
Oh wait, I know why.
I know why I'm so low on money.
It's because I spent 14,000 on an engine I can't even use.
This one.
That's why I'm so low.
For some reason, I thought I started out with 33,000.
And then bought this ship and now I was at 12,000.
Not bad.
Okay, dude.
We got the moon down.
But that's gonna happen next time.
Because I need to go eat.
I'm hungry AF.
Good time to stop here.
What do you think of that?
I think we got pretty far.
We lost Jebediah, man!
In the worst way possible, too.
Like, that was kind of a disgrace.
The way he died.
Right?
He deserved better than that.
But everything we do from now on is gonna be in his name.
Z theme gives you a dark mode UI.
Oh!
Okay, I gotta check that out then.
Maybe that's worth it.
Because the brightness of the UI actually is crazy when you're out in the dark, you know?
Okay.
Thank you, guys.
I'm gonna check that out.
I'm gonna write it down.
Z theme.
It has been noted.
Thank you.
Dude, this was incredible fun, wasn't it?
I mean, I sure had fun.
I don't know about you guys.
Do you have a mod list?
I do.
It's on YouTube.
If you look at the description of the first video, the mod list is there.
The only thing that's not in that list right now is restock, because I added that for today.
About the UI, maybe you can also have a keybine on OBS to hide the chat element when you hide the UI.
That's not a bad idea.
That's not a bad idea, actually.
That's actually a great idea.
But then again, I mean, the thing is, the chat is kind of essential for these VODs, because a live stream is like half the chat, you know?
The chat is half the live stream.
So when these amazing views happen, it's also cool to see the reactions of the people watching.
So, I don't know.
I'm kind of torn on that, actually, now that I think about it.
Maybe I can find a way to make the chat less intrusive.
Maybe that's the thing we can do.
Land on every planet in one flight?
That sounds crazy, bro.
What are you smoking?
I can't even land on the moon!
Well, I can't even get to the moon right now.
But next time.
Next time we're going to go to the moon.
And you know what?
I think that contract for the moon actually gives me a lot of money, too.
That's like the big thing with that.
I think it was like almost 100,000, you know?
So as soon as we get to the moon and do this, we're going to be so fucking back.
It's going to be good.
Is the stream over?
Yes.
We just finished.
Wait, we have a five-hour stream?
Dude, I thought it was three and a half.
Because Jackie hasn't been fed, man.
That was an hour ago.
I completely forgot about time.
Oh my god.
I'm sorry, Jackie.
I'm sorry.
She probably still has food in her bowl, though.
Like, whenever I feed her, she has like 20% of the food left from yesterday.
It's like she doesn't want that little bit, you know?
It's like me and beer.
When there's this lousy 10% left of the beer, I don't drink it.
It's nasty.
That's probably how she feels.
Yeah, Time Warp was turned on for this stream.
I am Adaine, the Danny boy.
I'm assuming you also are, given your name and question.
Beer Waster.
You're right, but it's only if I drink it slow.
If I drink it fast, it's not a problem.
It's because when it loses all the CO2 and it becomes hot and warm, you know, it's nasty at the bottom of the bottle.
I mean, I can force it down.
If someone offered me a beer, I would drink it all, you know?
Yeah, I'm a slow drinker when it comes to that.
Oh, you're Norwegian.
I see.
Belong in the football match?
Wait, what football match?
Oh, do we play in something?
I don't even know.
Like, I don't really follow sports.
Except esports.
And even then, it's a very narrow thing I follow in there.
I don't even know.
Is Denmark doing something cool right now in football?
Are we, like, in the world finals?
Oh, Norway versus Denmark?
Oh, okay.
I see.
I don't actually know who's better.
Like, I have no clue about football.
I know that Denmark won the European Championship in 92.
The year I was born.
But other than that, I'm clueless.
This game is a prime example of how mods can benefit a game 100%.
Mods, all in all, is always a net positive on a game.
I can't think of a single instance where mods is a bad thing for a game.
It's always a net positive.
Brings more people in.
It's just, it's long-term support.
You know, it's just love for the game.
It's amazing.
I was like that with tea.
The last five millimeter of a cup always had those nasty particles floating in it.
Yeah, actually, you're right.
I'm the same way, I guess, with tea.
But a lot of the time, I drink it without remembering that.
And then I'm like, oh, yeah, right.
It doesn't matter.
Norway has Ölgård and Haaland.
So I guess they're probably better.
Bro, those names mean nothing to me.
I don't know who that is.
I'm not a true Dane.
I don't even know our football team.
Haaland.
Guys, I'm gonna go eat some food.
My stomach is...
Now I understand why it's rumbling so much.
Because it's late.
This was five hours.
Like, gone like that.
And Tiagen used to be fed.
Thank you for watching.
This game is fucking incredible.
I can see this being an unbelievable series already.
Like, I'm blown away just by the future, the possibilities, and the ideas that I have in my mind right now.
It's absolutely bonkers.
Hoi!
Have a good one.
Thanks for watching.